So this section is all oriented around installation and setup.
Nothing very glamorous, but a lot of critical content that will need to move forward.
So the first thing we cover are the two main ways of using Git from the command line and from graphical
user interfaces.
That isn't a very important distinction to understand.
We'll be playing around with both throughout the course and then we focus on installing Git.
So I have separate instructions for Mac versus Windows users.
That's definitely going to be critical.
I marked it as yellow just because it can take a little bit of time.
If you're on a Windows machine, it's not hard.
You just have to change some settings and watch the video.
You'll see we just click a bunch of times and hit next and then hit next and then hit next.
But obviously very critical.
We also install an application called Get Crackin.
It's a game.
We forget it's free.
I guess it's not critical.
You don't have to use it if you want to use Git, but I'm going to put it as important slash critical
because for this course we'll be using this, but it is not critical to get itself configuring your
git name and email, critical but also very quick and easy.
And then the biggest question mark in this section is the terminal crash course videos.
There are three videos at the end of this section that are absolutely critical.
If you have no experience working with terminal command, basic UNIX, Unix commands like LHS and CD
and Touch.
So if you're familiar with those, you can skip those videos and they're not critical.
They're not really get specific at all.
So if you have experience, you can skip those, but it's all new to you.
I 100% would sit through them.
You don't need to take notes, but practice along with those videos.
They are very important.
If you want to be able to use get down the line.
We have to be able to navigate through the terminal.
So most things in this section are critical, but no big concepts.
It's just installation plus this weird thing at the end with the terminal.
I highly recommend checking that out if you're new.