Okay.
So now that we have installed Git, whether you're on a mac or a Windows machine, the next thing we
need to do is configure our name and email.
So we need to tell Git who we are, who it should attribute work to on our machine.
So this is not tied to an account necessarily.
There's no password.
You can make this whatever you want.
But let me just demonstrate the significance of setting up our name.
So if I'm working on a project with a bunch of people, for example, this is a project I have I really
haven't done anything sort of faking it.
It's, it's React, which is a very large JavaScript library.
I'm going to just run a quick command here and what you're looking at right now, full screen.
This is a log of different work, different check points on this application and who did them.
So here's one made by me, Colt Steel, but I can go back and see.
Here's some other work done by someone named Andrew Clark and somebody else did some other work.
Here's more.
Andrew Clark.
Here's Brian Vaughn.
So the point here is that so here's Dan Abramoff, pretty famous developer.
Anyway, the idea is that Git knows who did what work and who is making these checkpoints and these
changes.
So we need to configure that.
So this does not have to match some account that you have somewhere else.
However, I recommend that you use the name that you want to be known by as a developer.
If you are going to publish your work and put it up on GitHub, you want to use a name that people know
you buy or that will be consistent.
You don't want to be changing this all the time.
And then your email.
I recommend configuring with the email that you'll set up for your GitHub account if you haven't done
so well ready later in the course.
When we talk about GitHub, we can cross that bridge and you can always reconfigure these two values.
So here's how we do it.
The first step we'll do our name.
So all we do is get config and then dash dash global.
That's a way of telling git to set our username or our user name to be the same name across every time
we use git every instance.
But you can always change this.
So get config global username and then in quotes the name you want get to know you by.
So I can try this right now.
I'm not going to configure it.
I want to show you.
I can actually just check.
Do you have a user name for me already get?
If I run this command, I'm not setting it.
I'm asking and it says Yep, you're cold steel.
However, on my windows side if I do get config username I haven't configured one so it shows me nothing.
So I'm going to set that now.
So get config dash dash global username and then in quotes the name I want.
So get config dash dash global user name and I'll do cold steel.
Obviously you should put your name there.
I'm going to hit enter.
We don't really see anything happen, but now if I try and retrieve it, that's what this line does
get what is username?
It tells me cold steel and we're good to go now.
We're going to do the same thing for email, so it's the exact same pattern except user email and then
provide your email address.
So we'll try this.
It's the same process.
I'll do this on the Windows side, but whatever platform you're on, you want to do this, we'll do
get config user email.
Nothing is there.
But now I'm going to say get config dash dash global user email and then set it to be this is not my
real email but cult at gmail dot co.
Again, not my real email, but I recommend you put an email you have access to and especially when
we sign up for a GitHub account.
If you can foresee the email you would use for GitHub, I would use that email now, but we can always
change it.
It's the exact same line to change it.
So now I can recall the line from earlier.
If you don't know how to do this, hit the up arrow.
I can scroll through different lines up and down and I'm just going to verify.
Did it set?
And it did.
OC So that's all we needed to do.
Those two lines are going to tell Git who we are so that for future work, when we make changes, they
are attributed to whatever that user name and user dot email are set to.
All right.