Okay.
So this is an optional crash course on basic Unix commands.
If you are familiar with these commands, I'll run through them very quickly.
Things like LHS and P and CD and touch and mkdir make dear make dir r m our m dash ref.
If you know those commands already or you're familiar enough with them, then I would just skip the
next three videos.
Right?
You can always come back to these.
They have nothing to do with Git on their own, but they play a very important role.
And if you are not familiar with them, if you're new to the terminal when 100% stick it out through
these videos, I know it's not the most exciting thing on earth, but let's be honest, neither is Git.
It's very important, but it's not the sexiest topic.
So the reason this all matters is that I will be teaching git primarily from the command line, so I'll
be doing things like just as an example.
Everyone, I'm going to move into this folder here.
And to do that I would use the CD command, which we have not yet discussed.
And then and here I'd like to make a new file called my Apks JS file and then we'll run some git command
in here, do some git stuff again.
Haven't talked about any of this, but I'll do things like that and then we'll run another command and
then we'll back out.
The point is that we'll be navigating through the terminal, moving to different locations, different
folders, manipulating files, making changes, deleting creating things, and then interacting with
git.
From here we'll run commands that are specific to get and the folder that we're in.
So if you are comfortable with those basic commands, if already laid out, skip the next few videos.
If you're not if you're not familiar, don't freak out.
This is stuff that it's easy but it's it takes a bit of time for it to really stick.
The hardest part is remembering the commands.
So I recommend you just put some sticky notes up or a cheat sheet just to come back to these commands.
No one's expecting you to know them by heart.
After three videos, it takes a while for my bootcamp students in person at least to start working with
these commands like they're second nature because they're not.
It's kind of a horrible interface, but you force yourself to use it and you'll get comfortable.
Last thing I'll say is if you're on a mac, I'll be using the terminal app.
And if you're using a Windows machine as we installed Git, we set up get bash.
So my screen will look like this on the windows side.
Either one, the commands are 99.9% identical.
So if you see me do a command like LRS on the windows side or on the Mac side, they both are going
to do the same thing.
All right.
So let's get started.
Remember, completely optional, but I highly recommend sticking it out through these videos.
If you don't know the terminal commands, if you don't know the basic UNIX commands that I quickly ran
through c d touch make directory, rem, lz d those are going to be pretty important for the rest of
the course so that we can work with Git.
All right, I'll shut up.
Let's get started.