All right.
So the next group of commands I'm going to show you have to do with file and folder creation as well
as deletion or destruction.
So we've seen how to navigate around.
But another really important piece is being able to make new files.
So normally the way we would make a new file without the terminal would probably involve opening up
some application.
Like I use VS code, I have it open Visual Studio code and then I could go file new or just command
n and then start making a file, whatever type of file this is.
Let's say it's a JavaScript file.
I can put some JavaScript in it.
Hello.
It doesn't matter if you don't know JavaScript and then I can save this file and then I pick a destination.
Right.
And I give it a name like app JS with a dot JS extension and then I select somewhere for that to go.
That's the typical workflow for creating a new file.
If you're not doing it from a text editor or from some whatever, Excel or Photoshop or something,
you open an application and you create a file in the application.
But instead we can use a command called Touch Touch to Use.
It doesn't actually stand for anything like the other commands where we have CD is changed.
Directory touch is just touch.
It has a secondary use.
We're not really going to go into where you can touch a file that already exists and you're simply updating
the modified time.
It really doesn't matter for now if it helps.
Just think of it as a very weird name because it is very odd.
If I were designing it, there'd be a command called, I don't know, create or make or something.
Anyway, so all that we need to do is run, touch and then a space and then a file name or multiple
that we want to create.
And when we hit enter, wherever we currently are, whatever directory we're in, there will now be
a file in this case called Purple Text.
So I'll demonstrate this, I'll clear.
And I'm currently in my home directory so I can just make a file right here if I want to.
Why don't I open finder just so you have it, so you can see it over there?
I know it's not.
It's not that easy to read.
Unfortunately, this is the largest I can make these icons.
But you're not missing much.
Anyway, over here, I'm going to create a file.
What should we call this one?
How about Purple Dot?
JS So it's a JavaScript file called Purple.
So we don't really see anything changed.
But if I type LZ now we see a file that's been created and over here in my finder window I can see purple
JS so I can also make multiple at once.
I could do red text for a text file and orange.
What's another dot pi for a python file?
I could even make a PDF file.
These are all going to be completely empty.
Just an empty shell of a file with a name and an extension.
So what can I do?
Yellow dot pdf that just made me three files in one go.
Red, orange and yellow.
I can see them here if I run LZ or I can see them over here by inspecting them with my eyes.
I guess navigating.
I can see them purple, orange, red and yellow.
PDF.
It is a true pdf file.
My Mac is displaying the PDF icon.
I can do the same thing of course over here on my windows side.
Let's see.
We're just.
Whoops.
LS we're in the home directory, so I could make a file.
Here, let me clear this touch.
How about magenta dot txt?
If I type LZ, that will show up right there.
And if I go to the file explorer start.
Here it is magenta and it's a totally empty file.
And I could open it from here.
Select what to open it with.
Sure, notepad.
And then I can start working on it.
But I don't have anything to work on, so I'm just going to ignore that.
So that's the basic concept of touch.
The next thing I want to show you is how we can make new folders so touches, how we make new files.
We can make as many as we want in a single go.
Just separate the names by spaces.
Specify an extension.
And those files will be created in your current directory.
So I guess I should illustrate.
If I change directories into something else, for example, uh, what should I do?
Let's go on the window side.
I don't have anything on my desktop.
If I seed into desktop, I type LHS.
There's nothing there.
But if I touch a file, how about touch cyan dot js?
Now I have a file on my desktop and I'm sure I could show that to you.
Here it is the only file on my desktop.
So where I am when I run this command touch, that is where the file will be created.
Although you can actually create a file somewhere else that you're currently not inside.
For example, I could create a file instead of pets.
I am not in the pets directory.
All I need to do is touch and then the path to get to pets.
From where I am, I am in this folder so I would reference pets, which is somewhere here.
Where are you?
Here it is.
And then maybe inside of horses.
I could create a file so I could do touch pets.
Slash horses.
Slash.
How about Rocky Dot?
I don't know.
A PNG file which you normally wouldn't create an empty PNG, but there we go and we see it created over
here.
I'm not going to see it in my home directory.
It's not here.
I could seed into pets.
I still won't see it.
I could seed into horses and now I see it.
All right, so that's the basics of making files.
You can make them in a different location as long as you reference the correct path from where you are,
or you just make them in the current location where you are, whatever you see when you type.
If you try and create a new file with touch, dot, text or whatever the file is, you're creating it
in this location.
And there you are.
There's our second horse, good old Rocky, and asked your architect.
The next thing we need to know how to do is make folders.
So to make a directory the command is make dear or make dir.
I guess.
I guess you pronounce it directory.
So make dir.
I always say make dear in my head.
It doesn't matter.
MGK d i r.
So this command you follow it up with the name of directory you want to create.
It works in the same way as touch.
You can pass in multiple, separate them by spaces and by default they'll be created in your current
location, in your working directory.
So let's go to the pets directory right now.
I'm in this horses directory, so I'm going to back out and I want to make a new type of pet in this
directory.
So what should I do?
Frogs.
How about turtles?
So we'll make a new directory.
So not touch, but dear turtles and it doesn't have to be capitalized.
I'm just doing that because all these other directories are.
And if I show you over here, there's no turtles folder.
But now there is and it's empty.
So if I type ls I see turtles, I can see into turtles I can create a file in here.
What's a famous turtle?
I guess there's Lonesome George, who technically is a tortoise, but we'll make a file for him.
How about a Python file?
Great.
And then I could even make another folder in here, which I call this folder instead of turtles.
Let's make two directories.
How about sea turtles?
And this is actually an important note.
You don't want to put spaces in your names of files.
We want to, especially if we're using make directory.
It's going to think this is two directories we want to make.
See Space Turtles.
If you really wanted a space, you could do this with quotes.
But I don't recommend having spaces in there.
It just causes problems.
So do sea turtles.
Sea turtles like this sea underscore turtles.
It doesn't matter.
So I'll make a directory for sea turtles and then we'll just call them land turtles.
Sure.
I don't think that's the right term, actually, but here we are.
I now have two directories and a file inside of turtles.
So two empty folders I just made and then I can fill out their contents.
So let's make directory.
You just pass in a name.
I'll quickly demonstrate this on a Windows machine.
I'm on the desktop.
I'll make a folder here mkdir.
How about I don't know, cars?
And I'll do two at a time.
Cars and bikes.
And then if I want to view them, I could do LZ.
I see them right.
And they are visually represented differently, a different color, and then also a slash after their
name.
But I could also view my desktop and then I see the two empty folders plus my cyan file.
So that is make directory as well as touch.
Those are the two commands we saw in this video.
Just remember that they run relative to where you are.
So if you want to make a file in some folder, it's easiest if you navigate to that folder and you can
make 100 files at once using touch and then open up an editor or something to actually work on those
files.
Okay.
So next up, the last piece we're going to talk about deleting stuff.