Next up, let's talk about deleting files and folders.
This is the last important thing.
Well, there are other important commands, but this is the last of the fundamentals of working with
files and navigating.
So to delete a file, we have a command arm.
I assume it stands for remove and all we need to do is RAM and then a space and then reference a file
name.
Assuming that the file is in our current directory or we need to reference the correct path to get to
that file.
Now the thing you need to know up front is that this is not going to put it in your trashcan or your
recycling bin or whatever it's called.
This deletes the file.
It is gone.
So you want to be careful with this, right?
You don't want to go around deleting crucial files, although this is a good course and get can help
solve or alleviate these issues if you delete something accidentally.
If it was being tracked by Git, we can restore it with a single command.
It's very easy and painless.
Anyway, that's getting ahead of ourselves.
Let me demonstrate how this works.
Just remember this permanently deletes the file.
So what should we delete?
If you want to follow along, you might want to just make something to delete first so you could do
touch delete me.
So I didn't even give it a file extension.
If we look at it, where am I?
I'm in the turtles directory.
I could always do P to verify.
So that's right.
Here.
Here's the file I made.
I could even rename it from here.
How about we make it a dot d dock exe file which is Microsoft Word?
And it's going to ask me, are you sure you want to do that?
It doesn't matter.
I'm going to delete it.
But I wanted to show you, if you make modifications here, I could even rename this.
Delete me with a bunch of M or with a bunch of eas at the end if I type ls.
Now this is up to date as well, so to delete it it's just arm and then the name of the file.
And that's because I'm in this folder, so I don't need to reference some other path.
This is exactly what I need.
If I hit enter, you can see it disappears.
Whoops, that's not ls I meant to type?
LS It's gone so it's not coming back.
We're not using git right now.
So that is gone.
That that file is totally gone.
So let's make two more files to delete just really quickly.
How about delete dot txt and remove dot xls?
That's I think that's excel.
Maybe not.
Well, whatever that extension is, I thought it was Excel.
It doesn't matter.
I'm going to delete them, so I'll do them together.
They're both here.
You can see them.
There are them.
Delete text space removed xls.
They're both gone.
Quickly, I'll show it over here.
Let's delete this cyan file that I made on my windows side.
So here it is.
Cyan JS RMB Cyan JS if I type ls it does not show up here.
And if I look over here and the file explorer, it's not here.
I don't.
Maybe there's a way to make this larger.
There we go.
Well, still, it's not here.
Okay, so the next thing I want to talk about is deleting folders.
If I want to delete this folder, land turtles right there.
I cannot use the M command as it stands.
Land turtles like that it says nope.
Land turtles is a directory rmm delete files or at least our RAM the way we used it.
So we actually have a variation of RAM in order to delete a folder or a directory or RAM dash.
RF We haven't talked about flags.
This is just a crash course in the basic terminal navigation, the essential commands you need to know.
But all of the commands we've used actually accept a bunch of options that modify how they behave.
So as a quick example, LS actually has a couple of other variations.
One is LS Dash A which is going to show me hidden files so that Dash A modifies the behavior of LRS.
It says list all files including hidden hidden files.
Start with a dot so there's a hidden file.
This will actually come up when we make a git repository.
It makes a hidden directory for us anyway, getting ahead of myself.
So these flags are different options we can pass in and there are two we will use on prem if we want
to delete a directory r and F, we don't need to go too much into what they mean.
They stand for recursive.
That's the R and force is the F.
Basically this is how we delete a folder.
But you want to be careful with this because just like with deleting a file from the command line or
from the terminal, it's gone.
So if you delete a directory that's full of important stuff and it's not backed up somewhere, it's
not in the cloud, it's gone.
That's kind of end of story.
So let's say I want to delete the entire turtles directory.
Why don't I start by deleting land turtles?
I didn't mean to type this, by the way, so I want to delete land turtles again.
REM land turtles does not work, but rem dash r f land turtles will.
It's gone.
There's no land turtles here.
But that was an empty directory.
If I try and delete turtles, which itself has it doesn't have a lot but turtles has sea turtles folder
and george p a file.
I'm now in the directory above it.
I'm in pets so I'm going to try deleting it.
So I'll clear, by the way on a mac that shortcut, if I have a bunch of stuff to clear is command k.
Anyway, I'm in the pets directory and if I want to delete turtles ram dash, R.F. Turtles.
So you'll see it over here.
There it is.
And there it goes.
It's gone.
And that's it.
I can't navigate into turtles.
It doesn't exist.
No such file or directory.
But remember, I need the dash ref to do that if it's a folder.
If it's just a file, I just do.
And either way, those are gone.
They're gone for good.
So be careful.
You know, don't go around running this command on very important files and folders.
Just always take a moment to think about what you're doing because you don't have that intermediate
step of dragging something to the trash.
But not much of this course really relies on deleting stuff.
To be honest, it's mostly creating things and tracking those things with get and changing those files.
So it's not like we're going around deleting a bunch of stuff.
I just figured you should know about those commands because they will come up every so often.
All right, so that's our M and our M dash RF.
They're both the same command.
Just a variation to delete folders.