Okey dokey.
It's time to learn our first command.
That has to do with branching.
And it's pretty simple.
One, it is get branch, get space branch, nothing else.
This will just give us a list of our current existing branches in a repo so it doesn't make a new branch,
it doesn't switch branches, it just shows you the current branches.
In our case, we haven't made new branches, so we won't see anything except Master.
So I'm on my first novel for now.
I'm going to make a new repository in a moment.
If I type git branch, I see one branch master and to get out of here, just like with git log I type
q.
Now I'll show you a different project.
This repository has a couple more branches.
If I type git branch, you can see them all here.
Birds.
Birds of prey.
California mammals.
Hawks.
Mammals.
Master no animals.
Owls.
Stash test.
I was testing something out there.
You can see though, there's a bunch of branches, but the one that is active has a little asterisk
next to it.
That's the branch we're currently on.
So we see I'm on owls and again I can type Q to get out of here.
So here on my first novel project, we only have Master.
I never made that branch and it's the only branch we have, so we're on it.
We don't really have a choice right now.
But next up, we're going to learn how to make a new branch.