All right.
So next up, we're going to learn how to make our first branch.
And we actually use the same command that we just saw get branch, except now we add on a branch name.
So get branch with a branch name, we'll create a branch with that name versus Git branch without anything
else.
Just lists the current branches.
So get branch branch name and your branch name.
We'll talk a little bit more about later, but it shouldn't include spaces.
Let's just start with that.
And generally you want it to make sense and be informative, but you don't need to write a whole sentence
to explain what the branch is.
Also, this simply makes a branch for us.
It does not switch to the branch.
So I'm on my master branch here.
As you can see, head points at master.
I have two commits on the master branch when I run this command to get branch bug fix.
That makes me a new branch called Bug Fix.
It's based off of the head where I currently was, so it points to the same exact spot.
But I have a new branch.
I have not switched to it.
I'm still on, master.
So I'll demonstrate this to you.
Let's make a new branch.
But first, I'm actually going to work on a separate project, a separate repo.
Instead of working on the novel.
We were writing The Great Gatsby.
I'm going to make a new repo.
I'm in a folder.
I'm just calling it branching and I'm going to make a directory.
I'm going to make a road trip playlist folder.
So often when I'm teaching this stuff, I'm torn if I should do something.
Very easy to follow along with.
Something simple to understand.
Or if I should do something realistic, I'm going to try and do both.
But I'm going to start with the super simple, easy to understand project.
So it's not really a project.
We're going on a road trip and I want a playlist of songs and I'm going to use Git for whatever reason
to track those songs and I'll make some different branches.
So I'm going to start by making my repository.
So I'm in a folder, road trip playlist.
I'm going to run, get it.
So I have an empty repo.
I know that I wasn't in a git repo, but I should have checked to see with git status.
But I know that I wasn't.
And then I'm going to go ahead and make a file.
I'm going to call it playlist.
Dot txt and I'll open this up in my editor.
So here it is.
I'm just going to start by adding a very simple heading like song artist.
So it's just the header heading for the playlist.
All right, I'm going to add that file, get add playlist, get commit.
I'm on the master branch, of course, just by default.
Add playlist header.
All right, we type get log.
We see head is pointing to the master branch.
Now I'm going to add two songs just to add songs to start that I happen to like.
There they are songs.
Great song, one of us also great song.
I'm going to add those.
I just want to have one or two commits on my master branch.
So I'm going to do git add playlist, get commit, add to Abi's songs.
All righty.
So I'm on the master branch, right?
Head points to master.
We have two commits.
Now let's make a new branch.
For whatever reason I decide I want to make a different playlist based on this one that only contains
oldies.
So maybe I'm not sure what I want on my main playlist, so I'm going to try a couple of options, and
that's exactly what I'm going to do, is make some different branches and I'm going to make a branch
called oldies, and it's just going to include songs that are they're not technically what the radio
would classify as oldies, but let's just say anything from before, like 2000, which I recognize for
most people is not oldies.
So to make a branch, get branch and then a branch name.
So let's make that oldest branch get branch, I'll make this full screen.
And then actually before I do that, let's just do Git Branch.
We're on master.
It's the only branch now if I do get branch oldies.
And hit enter.
Hmm.
It doesn't seem like anything happened.
I'm still on, Master.
If I type get status, I'm still on master.
No surprise there.
It doesn't switch us over.
But if I type get branch, we do see we have a new branch oldies.
We're just not on it.
Head is still pointing to master.
You can see that again type get log head is pointing to master.
But now we have this new reference oldies.
It's at the same commit right to branch references pointing to the same thing.
We just happen to be on master.
So we're at this stage two branches.
They're both referring to the same point, the same commit and we're on master.
So to switch branches, there's a command that we can use called get switch.
So this is actually a newer command in Git.
I'll do a separate video on the older command.
We used something called Git Checkout to do the same thing.
We'll talk about that.
It's still used in other contexts, but get switch was introduced to switch between branches, so get
switch and then a branch name.
So in our example here, if I do get switch bug fix head is now pointing to that bug fix branch.
It was on master, now it's on bug fix.
So in our case we have this oldest branch, we are not on it.
We see that we're on master type get status, we're on master.
But if I do get switch oldies and I do need to spell it correctly so if I reference something that doesn't
exist, it tells me there's no branch with that name.
But if I do get switch oldies.
Hey switch to branch oldies.
My terminal shows oldies over here.
If I type get status on branch oldies and if I type git log you can now see head is pointing to oldies.
Still the same commit though I haven't done any new work.
However, if I do some new work and make a new commit here, this is the oldies playlist.
So what should we add?
Let's add to good great George Jones songs.
He stopped loving her today.
Great song.
So I'm going to save and I'm going to commit now when I commit here, remember, I'm on the Old East
Branch, so get add playlist, get commit, add to George Jones songs just like that.
And we just made our first commit on a new branch.
We're on the oldest branch and if I type get log, we're going to see something we haven't yet seen.
We see head referring to oldies.
That's what we expect to see.
It's our most recent commit.
That's where oldest is because we're on the oldest branch.
But we see Master now has been left behind on this previous commit.
Master is still remember this idea of a bookmark in the book.
It's still bookmarking this commit.
This is master, this is oldies and we happen to be on the oldest branch.
But I can switch as we've seen with git switch.
So if I switch right now this is what we have on our oldest branch.
If I switch over, get switch to master.
Take a look.
Now we have just two lines, just two songs, rather.
We don't have the George Jones stuff that we did.
If I type, get log on the master branch.
We only have these two commits, add the playlist header, add two ABBA songs, but when I switch back,
get switch to oldies.
We now have our two George Jones songs in addition and I type get log, we have that extra commit.
So that was just our first example of making a branch and switching.
We will get more practice in the next video, but just to remind you, get branch on its own, we'll
list branches, get branch with a branch name, makes a branch and then to switch to a branch we use
git switch followed by the branch name.