In this video.
We'll continue to make some more branches.
And I'm also going to show you another way, another command we can use to make and switch to a branch.
But first, I want to pay special attention to this part of the the first paragraph here.
You get branch with a branch name to make a new branch based upon the current head.
That part is super important.
It tells us that where we are, what head is, when we create a branch, impacts the branch that we
create.
So the location, the current branch we're on when we branch is very, very important and makes a huge
difference.
So for example, here I've got my road trip playlist.
I don't want to call it an app, but our repo, just from the previous video and I'm currently on the
oldest branch I Typekit log.
I have the commits from master these two and then I have the new commit I added on the oldest branch.
So I'm going to add, how about two more songs?
George Harrison Songs, My Sweet Lord, and what is Life by George Harrison?
And I'm going to add and commit those and I'm actually going to do it in a different way.
I haven't showed you a dash cam is basically a one line way of adding all on stage changes.
So get commit dash a instead of add and then commit.
And then I'll provide my message.
Just add to George Harrison's songs.
All right.
So now I have another commit that I've added to the oldest branch.
So if I branch right now and make a new branch, let's say I make a George's branch I want to make yeah,
I guess a playlist that only includes songs by George's.
I can do that.
I'll branch from the oldest branch.
That's where I am right now.
So I can do git branch George's.
So I made that branch.
Of course I'm still on oldies I haven't switched over, but if we look at git log we see that both oldies
and my new branch George's.
They are both referring to the same commit.
They're at the same spot.
The same page has been bookmarked with two different bookmarks.
Head is currently pointing to oldies, but if I want to switch to George's and make a commit on George's,
of course they will diverge.
So if I switch over, get switch to George's.
We go get log.
Only thing that has changed here is that head now points to George's and I have all those commits from
the earlier oldest branch on Georges, so now I can do a bit more work.
I'll add what's another add to George Michael songs.
Okay, so there we go.
Careless Whisper and Faith by George Michael.
I'll just add and commit them to the same thing a m Add to George Michael songs.
And this of course only goes on the George's branch.
That's the branch I'm currently on.
So now if I type git log, what do we expect to see?
Head refers to George's because I'm on the George's branch and I have this one commit that only exists
on the George's branch and the oldest branch was left in the dust back here.
Right, so I could switch back to oldies get switch all these and we see we lose those two songs also.
You know, I actually left in those ABBA songs, so I should switch back to George's.
And I want to delete those ABBA songs because they're not created by George's, and unfortunately we're
only allowing George's here.
So now I'll do another get ad and get comments or just the short version.
I'm on the George's branch.
So don't forget that.
Remove to ABBA songs.
All right, so now get log.
I have these two new commits on the George's branch that I'm currently on, plus all the other commits
from the oldest branch at that moment in time when I split.
So just at that moment in time, if I do more work on oldies, it does not impact George's OC.
So now I go back to oldies, get switch oldies, and we see ABBA is back and we don't have George Michael.
If I go back to Master, almost everything's gone.
We just have ABBA.
So if I make one more branch from here, just as a quick demo, it's going to be based upon master that
I currently am.
So I know I'm beating this dead horse a lot, but it's really important where you branch from matters.
And if I make a new branch get branch, what should this one be?
How about just an empty playlist?
Get branch.
Empty playlist.
I now have this branch referring to the same spot as master.
And now I'll switch over, get switch empty playlist.
And here we are.
So now I can delete everything if I wanted to.
Get commit a m.
Empty Out playlist.
And there we go.
If I look at the log, I only have three commits, the two from master and then the one new one.
Anyway, this has been a long demonstration, but I just wanted to show it does matter where you branch
from.
So we go back to master.
If I whoops I get switch master.
We have ABA.
If I go back to George's get switch George's.
There we are.
And if I get switch back to empty playlist, that's all we've got.
OC.