All right.
So next up, I want to talk about a different command you may come across that we can use to switch
branches.
It's called git checkout.
You can see it here.
Get checkout with a branch name.
Will do the exact same thing as git switch with the same branch name.
It just switches us to whatever this branch name is.
So this command git checkout existed for a long time.
It still exists in GITS and it does a lot more than just switching branches.
So it's kind of a Swiss army knife of git that doesn't do everything.
I guess neither does a Swiss army knife, but it does a lot more.
And for a lot of users, this was confusing and just it felt like it did too many things.
So get switched was introduced.
It's newer.
So the command we've been using Git switch is the newer, fancier way of switching branches.
But this is the old school way and it still works.
And I'm showing it to you because you'll still see this for sure all over the place in documentation
or on blog posts, YouTube videos, that sort of thing.
Coworkers might use get check out to switch branches plus git switch is still liable to change, although
it's been around now for a little while.
I don't expect it to.
So let me just demonstrate this.
I'm on empty playlist.
I can see I've got my four branches.
Let's switch to oldies.
So instead of get switch, I'll do get checkouts oldies.
And the same behavior I'm now on.
The oldest branch, as we can see there in my file, has been updated to reflect what's on the oldest
branch.
So that's kind of all there is to using git checkout in that one particular way.
But remember, git checkout does a lot more.
You can read about it on the docs, although I really recommend you don't read it right now.
Just know this first part.
We can use it to switch branches, but then there's this whole other thing restore working tree files,
look at all the different options for how we use it.
We will get into check out later on.
But in terms of switching branches, it's very, very simple.
With that said, I still prefer get switch.
Now, another thing that we can do is instead of creating a branch and then switching to it in two separate
steps, we can do it all in one go.
We can do it with git switch if we add dash C as an option for create.
So we provide a branch name and it will create that branch and then switch us over to it all at once.
So this can be pretty useful in my opinion.
Let's make a new branch from let's go back to master maybe so we'll go back to master.
Will you switch or check out?
It doesn't matter.
All right.
So I'm going to make my new branch with this shortcut I showed you.
Get switch dash C and then a branch name that doesn't exist yet.
So I'll switch.
I'm going to call it recent ish music.
Like that and notice it made it and I switched to it.
So without the dash C it would give me an error, right?
Just like this error.
It can't find that branch to switch to.
But with dash see it makes the branch for me and then switches over and I'll just add two songs for
some recent music.
I'll remove Abba, Phoebe, Bridgers, by the way, if you don't know her, a very talented singer songwriter
and I'll just add and commit that I'll do it in two steps this time.
Add to Phoebe Bridgers songs.
There we go.
And that's kind of all I wanted to show you here.
Now there is an equivalent command if you use git checkout, but unfortunately it's git checkout dash.
B b as in boy.
B for branch.
It's very confusing.
I don't know why they went with Dash B, but it's just how it works.
If you want to make a branch and check it out in one, go get checkout dash B or get switched dash C
and again, I prefer this, but you'll see git checkout used.
All right, so we've got some pretty good practice now, making branches and switching, making new
commits on separate branches, switching between them.
Hopefully it's clear or at least becoming clear how this all works.
One thing, though, that my limited example has not illustrated is that we can have as many files as
needed.
Right?
I don't want you to think that branches exist on a per file basis.
We do see this one file being updated, but I could make another file on one of these branches and git
will make sure that it exists on that branch and does not exist on the other branches or get will update
all relevant files and folders depending on the branch, so it's not limited to just one file, even
though my simple demo has been.
All right.
So that's it for this video.