This is going to be a very quick video.
I just need to explain one thing that we haven't run into yet.
If I'm on a branch and I have some work that is not currently committed, so let's go to the oldest
branch, get switch oldies and I'll do some work here.
Like I'll add two Van Morrison songs, great songs, and it's done Me and Caravan, so I'll save those
too.
But I'm not going to add in commits.
So over here I see get status.
I modified that I have changes that are not staged.
There's work on this branch that has not been committed.
If I try and switch branches right now, let's see what happens.
Let's go back to the how about our empty playlist, get switch empty playlist and what does it say?
I get an error.
Your local changes to the following files would be overwritten by checkout playlist.
TXT It's telling me that the work I have done right now that I have not yet committed, which is right
here.
If I try and switch to a different branch, it's going to be lost because it's not committed.
This branch doesn't know about it.
There's not going to be a bookmark for it in the really large book before we change pages.
So it says Please commit your changes or stash them.
We will learn more about stashing in just a couple of sections from now.
So for now, that's not an option.
For now, our only option is to commit our work or just delete it, I guess, and not make those changes.
So I am going to commit that get add playlist, get commit Dash Am, add two Van Morrison songs.
Just like that.
And now I can switch so I can do the same command to switch to empty playlists.
No complaints.
So if you run into an issue like this, hopefully you understand why.
Now get is warning you you're going to lose those changes.
You either need to stash them, which we haven't learned or commit them.
Now, the last example I showed you, we had changes that were in conflict, right?
When I tried to switch branches, we were working on the same file, this playlist file, and they were
in conflict.
And so get yelled at me and said, Hey, I don't know what to do.
We'll learn more about conflicts when we get to merging, but sometimes that's not an issue at all.
So if I make a new file, for example, I'm on the oldest branch.
Let me make a new branch here, get switch C and this branch will be.
I don't know.
How about chicken?
I'm going to delete it.
A chicken branch.
And on this chicken branch, I'm going to make a new file entirely called chickens txt and I'll put
some of my chickens in here like Stevie Chicks.
So I have this new file no other branch has, but I haven't added or committed that file.
And so now if I switch again, let's go back to oldest get switch oldies.
Previously at the beginning of this video we saw that get yelled at me when I tried to switch and it
says You can't switch.
You have changes that are going to be overridden that you're in conflict.
We don't know what to do.
Please stash or commit them.
But this is going to be different because no other branch has this file.
There's no way that it's in conflict with anything.
So what actually will happen is this this file is going to come with me.
I'm now on the oldest branch.
And I still have chickens.
You see that?
The file is still there.
And it came with me and it still says, Hey, there's this untracked file.
You haven't made it commit with it anywhere.
It's just going to follow you to every branch you go to.
So for now, I'm just going to recommend we always add and commit changes before we switch branches
so that we can avoid this.
But of course, like I said, we're going to learn how to stash changes very soon.
First, we're going to learn about merging, but I just want to call your attention to this behavior.
When you switch branches, sometimes, if you have unstaged changes, they will come with you.
Other times, if they're in conflict, get will yell at you.
So just know that.