Okay.
In this video, I want to talk about deleting and renaming branches.
So this is something you probably won't need to do all that often early on at least.
But if you work professionally or you work on a large project where there's tons of branches and you
are constantly making new branches and then merging them in again, we haven't talked about merging,
but it's really common to work on something and then merge it in.
You don't want to just have this extra branch for no reason so you can delete them.
Let's talk about how you delete a branch.
You use the git branch command get branch does a lot and we've seen it shows us a list of branches.
It also creates a new branch and we can delete using git branch with the dash dx option.
So dash dx or dash dash delete deletes the branch.
Now it tells us this message here it must be fully merged, blah blah blah.
We will learn more about what this means shortly.
We haven't talked about merging, but if I try and delete one of these branches, for example, let's
make a new branch so I'll go full screen here.
Where are we?
We are on empty playlist.
It's an empty branch.
Let's go to, I don't know, the Georges branch, so get switch Georges and then let's make a new branch
and I'll use our single line version, get switch dash C to create a new branch and I'm going to call
it delete me because I know I want to delete it.
So we're on this new branch, delete me and to delete it I use the dash dx option on git branch.
So let's try it get.
Branch.
DX And then I specify the branch to delete, which is delete me.
I'm going to run into a problem.
I can't delete the branch I'm checked out at or the one that I'm viewing.
Right?
I'm on delete me.
I can't delete it.
So if I switch branches, let's do get switch master and I try running that again.
Now I get a different message.
It's not fully merged.
If you are sure you want to delete it, run git branch dash uppercase rd which is equivalent to adding
in the dash dash force option.
In other words, allow deleting the branch irrespective of its merged status.
So in this case, that's fine.
You want to be confident in what you're deleting and that you actually do want to delete it because
without GitHub, without any sort of backup, which we don't have at this point in time, if I had a
lot of work on this branch and I actually delete it, it's gone.
But for this demonstration I'm fine deleting it.
So git branch uppercase rd delete me and now it's gone.
So we can see here there is no delete me, branch.
All right.
Now, another thing we might want to do is rename a branch, and this is something we definitely will
be doing when we get to GitHub.
We could rename our master branch to Main to play well with GitHub, but also it's a common thing to
do if you're unhappy with the branch name or you just want to change it and give it a better name.
The way that we do it is somewhat hard to remember.
We use Git branch the same command.
However, the flag or the option that we use is dash m and that seems somewhat confusing.
It doesn't.
It should be dash R for rename or dash dn for name, but it's actually dash M for move, but it's moved
slash rename.
So all that we do if we want to rename a branch is first change to the branch that we want to rename.
So this is kind of confusing because to delete a branch we had to go anywhere else but that branch we
could not delete from the branch.
But to rename you have to be on the branch.
Again, it's just kind of weird, but you don't have to do this that frequently.
So what branch should I rename?
How about instead of recent ish music?
I just want to rename it to two thousandths.
So music from the 2000s.
Because recent ish implies something somewhat pretty recent.
But maybe I want anything from the 2000s.
So I'm going to switch, get switch and I'll do check out this time just to mix it up, show you both
work recent ish music I switched OC and now I'm going to rename it with Git Branch Dash M and then my
new name which will be two thousandths OC and we can see already it changed to 2000s over here.
If I type get status on branch two thousandths get log.
We see that head is pointing to 2000 as the branch name.
It's the same branch that I was on before.
The same two Phoebe Bridgers songs are here, but it's been renamed from recent ish music to two thousandths.
So I'll do, I guess one more commit.
Here are two songs by a great group called Motor Rat and I will go ahead and commit Dash a dash m just
to do it in one go add to it songs.
All right.
And so that only exists on the 2000s branch.
It no longer is called recent ish songs or recent ish music.
OC So that's how you can rename a branch.
It's Dash.
M Where are you?
Where did I do it?
Right here.
It's somewhat confusing, but it works.
It stands for MOVE and then we have Dash DX to delete a branch to operations.
You may not need to do all that often.
Certainly not right now, but good to know about.