This video is completely 100,000,000 trillion percent optional.
Please, if you don't care to watch it, don't.
We're not going to learn any new commands or any new syntax.
All that I'm going to do is show you a little peek behind the scenes in Git.
We're going to take a look at that dot git directory and I'll show you proof of head how it works.
The fact that it's just referencing a branch and that each branch reference is referencing a commit.
All right.
So let's go ahead and hop over here to our road trip playlist.
We are on this 2000 branch.
Let's go back to master.
So get switch master and on master.
It's very simple.
We have two commits and that's it.
And we can see that head is referring to master because we're on the master branch and the master branch
is pointing to this commit.
This is the most recent commit on the tip of the master branch.
Let's take a look at this commit hash.
It starts with 93e.
Let's just remember that 93ed 93 OC.
So remember that.
And now remember we have this hidden directory called Git and inside of it I'll just seed inside seed
dot git.
We have this thing called head and head.
If I take a look I'm just going to use the cat command is referencing this other thing refs slash heads
slash master.
So in other words this is I'll simplify it head is pointing to the master branch if I switch branches
get switch oldies whoops can't do that from here.
I have to back out now if I switch because I was in the docket directory, gets very confused, get
switched to oldies and now I take a look again.
So I'll do cats dot git slash head.
I'm now outside that folder.
See this?
It now references oldies.
So if I switch back to Master.
And I take a look at head.
It's now master.
So that thing, that file called Head is just referencing a particular branch.
Now this thing here, refs slash heads slash master or refs slash heads slash oldies right here.
They actually reference a particular commit.
So let's take a look.
I'm going to open up the docket directory now.
I've opened up the git directory just in finder here and let's take a look at this.
Refs slash heads slash master.
So refs heads and you'll see there's a file for every branch that I have.
And in each one of these files, there's just one thing.
I'm going to open it in my text editor.
It's just a commit hash it's just a pointer to a particular commit and head in turn is pointing to one
of those branch references.
So remember head was reps, slash heads, slash master.
That's what it had inside.
And then if we look at what that actually is.
It's a comet 93 E RD.
That is where the master branch left off.
That's where the bookmark for master branches.
Now, if I switch to the oldest branch, nothing changes in this master reference.
Right.
But we know that my head changed so we could take a look at that again.
Cat dot get slash head.
There it is.
Head slash oldies and if we look at that.
All this.
It says the last commit on the oldest branch is seven FD and if we type git log, that's exactly what
we see.
Seven FD.
Right, so we can see that all over the place.
I have this 2000 branch and it says the last commit on there zero to F four OC.
And so if we switch to that branch get switch two thousandths.
Typekit log.
There it is.
There are 2f4.
So each one of these is like a bookmark.
It's one of these branch references.
So we happen to have what, five of them instead of two?
In this diagram, each one refers to a commit.
It just stores that commit hash in a file and then head changes.
This file right here changes depending on what we have checked out, which branch we're currently on.
So again, this really doesn't matter if you understand it or not.
In terms of using Git, it's not a big deal as long as you understand the fact that head is just whatever
you're currently checked out on, whatever you're what branch you're on.
But behind the scenes, this is the mechanism.
It's just a file and it references a particular branch reference.
We look at those branch references, they in turn refer to a particular commit.
So pretty simple when you look at it this way.
So hopefully this diagram plus this starts to sort of congeal branch reference points to a commit,
this one points to a different commit head, just points to one of those branch references so we can
stay on dark mode or I could toggle back to master, but these stay the same.
The branch reference, they both stay the same head is all that's changing until I do more work and
make new commits anyway.
So the optional I'm sure I'm boring you to death, so I'm going to stop by.