All right.
So it's time for an exercise to get some practice with get branches.
So this is going to be a simple exercise in terms of the files we're working with, kind of silly.
It's Harry Potter themed, but it doesn't matter if you know Harry Potter or don't if you just follow
the instructions and make the branches.
When you're prompted to make branches and switch branches, when you're prompted to switch, you should
be good to go.
Now, the theme of this, aside from Harry Potter, is of Harry Potter Patronages, which are like,
I guess a Harry Potter version of a spirit animal.
If you've seen the movie or read the books, the spell expected petroleum, I don't even know why I'm
going into it.
It doesn't matter anyway.
Wizards have their own patronus different animals.
So you will be putting some animals in files on different branches for different characters.
So again, I strongly recommend you do this on your own.
Follow the instructions you can find this file link to in the resources for this video.
You're going to make a new directory, make a new git repo inside of it, make sure you're not already
in one, then you'll create a new file called Petronas txt and you'll leave it empty for now.
So this will be on your default branch, the master branch or if you've changed the default name, whatever
it is main.
But for now the default is just master.
Then we'll make our first commit with this message.
Add empty patronus file.
Then we'll make a new branch called Hairy and at the same time, or in the next line, a second new
branch called Snape.
Both of them should be based on the master branch.
They should contain this empty patronus file.
Then you will move to the hairy branch that you just made.
And there are two different ways we've talked about for moving to new branches or moving between branches.
So I would like you to use the new command.
If you don't remember which one is new and old, it's not a big deal.
Just use one of the commands that we talked about and then later on use the other command that you didn't
use.
So on the hairy branch, we are going to put this inside of the Patronus file.
Harry Potter's Patronus is a stag, so copy all of this and put it in that file, save it, add and
commit the changes and then use this message.
Add Harry Stag Patronus and again this is on the Harry branch.
Then you will move over to the other branch you already made called Snape.
So this branch again should be based off of master when you made it early on, at the same time as the
Harry branch, when you move over to that branch, use the other command, the older command, to switch
or to change branches and then open up the Patronus file again.
And this time put this in there.
Snape's Patronus is a doe, so this is what you'll put in there, save it, add in commits and then
use this message if you'd like.
Then something different.
We will make a new branch based upon the Snape branch and we're going to call it Lily.
If you don't know any of these characters, it really doesn't matter.
All you need to know is that Snape and Lily have the same patronus.
So we are branching off of Snape to a new branch called Lily, and then we will move to that branch,
to the Lily branch, and we'll edit this file and we're going to keep the DOE in there because they
have the same patronus.
But we will edit this little header so that it says Lily's patronus instead of Snape's.
You can leave the DOE alone.
That's the point.
They share the same patronus the same form.
Then you'll add and commit.
You can use this message if you want.
So this is on the lily branch.
Then run a command to list all the branches.
You should see four.
So just making sure you remember that command.
And then as a bonus, delete the Snape branch.
Poor Snape.
Okay.
So if you're still here, I really recommend.
I insist that you try it on your own.
But if you want to, just watch me do it.
Here we go.
So I'm going to make a new folder called Petronas.
Let's just do that here.
Petronas.
I'll seed into it.
I'm going to initialize a repo, but first make sure I'm not in one.
Okay.
So now I have this folder and a new repo in it and I'm going to create a file called Petronas txt,
Petronas Dot txt and then I'm going to add and commit with this message add empty Petronas file.
So get add that file, get commit m there's my message and there we go.
That's the first bit.
Now immediately make a new branch called Hairy and another new branch called snip, both based on the
master branch I'm currently on master, so that works to our advantage.
I'm going to make a new branch called Hairy and another one called Snake OC.
Next step move to the hairy branch using the new way of doing it.
The new command is get switch so we'll move over using git switch to the hairy branch and now we see
that we're on hairy.
Then in the Petronas file add the following.
So I need to open up that file so I'll do a copied all of that first of all, but then I'll use my code
shortcut code.
Just do the whole folder.
Here's that Petronas File.
I will paste that in there.
Let me zoom out a bit.
Okay.
So I'll save that and then it wants me to add and commit the changes with this commit message.
All right.
So we'll do a git, add Petronas, get commit m and paste in that message.
Okay.
So we should now have two commits on this branch.
Next, we are going to move over to the snake branch using the other the older command, which is git
checkout.
So we'll do that.
Get checkout snip.
You could use switch that right there.
Both going to work.
But I just want you to get practice with both.
So I'm now on the snake branch as my terminal tells me and I'm going to put this in the Patronus file.
Now, if I take a look, the Patronus file is empty, right?
Because I branched off of Master before anything was in here.
I didn't branch from the Harry Potter or the Harry Branch.
I'll save that.
And then I'm going to make a new commit.
With that change and this message.
So get add Petronas get commit dash em on the snake branch, add Snape's Doe, Petronas and then I need
to make a new branch based on the snake branch called Lili and then move to it.
So I could just do git branch.
Lily I'm on snake and that's where I should be.
If I want to branch based on Snape, I want this history.
Just to remind you, if I do a get log to commits, add empty file, add snape's doe patronus.
So if I do a git branch lily that will work or I can make the branch and switch to it in one go like
this get switched dash see lily and that made it and it switched me over.
I still see add snape's doe patronus.
Right.
The file contains the doe.
Now I'm going to edit it so that it says Lily's Patronus instead of snape's.
So I'll put that up top and then I will add and commit.
So just copy this message.
Get status.
We modified Petronas so we add, we commit and we'll give it that message.
OC Next and almost at the end run a get command to list all branches we should see four.
So what does that command?
It's just get branch and nothing else.
Just get branch.
We see four I'm currently on Lily and then bonus delete the Snape branch.
Oh poor Snape.
Well to delete a branch we saw that we use the exact same command get branch and then a branch name
but we pass in this dash dx, get branch dash dx and then Snape, that's the name of the branch.
Make sure I'm not on that branch.
I'm currently not.
And there we go.
It was deleted.
So now if I do just regular get branch only three branches and that's it.
That's the end of the branching exercise OC.