I hope you survive the previous section.
There's a lot of really important stuff in there.
Maybe take a break before moving on to this one.
I don't really have a real title for this section.
I'm calling it committing in more detail, but it's more than that.
This section does cover some more stuff around committing, but also there are some assorted gifts topics
thrown in here that didn't really fit anywhere else neatly.
So let's talk about what actually matters.
We're going to talk about something called atomic commit writing atomic commits.
That sounds scarier than it is.
It's just an approach as to how you break down commits.
We'll say it's important, but I would stress about it not critical.
If you're on a Windows machine when we installed it, we also configured VTS code to be the default
editor.
If you're on a mac that was not part of the installation process, it didn't prompt us for that.
So if you're on a mac, it's going to be important to configure the default editor and I use VTS code.
I'll show you how to do that.
If you're not on a mac, you probably already did it.
Working with a graphical user interface.
I like showing it.
A lot of students enjoy it, but 100% optional, not essential to using git.
It's one option, but you could go your whole life without ever touching a gooey amending commits will
say it's nice to have it's useful, but especially early on not that common that you would need this.
Now get ignore I'll say is a pretty critical part of working with git still early on not a big deal
but when you work with get in the real world get ignores are very important.
I haven't even explained what it is but just trust me.
That thing critical writing good commit messages will say it's important but again not like a fundamental
thing.
More of a matter of taste and opinion.
And then navigating the git documentation, we'll say important as well, but not critical.
I'm not really a big fan of the get docs, honestly.
They're they're very intimidating.
So as you can see, it's kind of a mixed bag here.
There are some nice to have that I still recommend watching, but amending commits for example, working
with a gooey I don't think they're all that important but working with good ignores and then some good
practices for writing commits, writing atomic commits, writing good commit messages worth your time,
but don't freak out about it.
So let's get started.