So let's start the section off with a nice and easy topic.
The get docs.
Yes, this is a very funny joke because these are pictures of doctors, but we're not actually talking
about doctors.
We're talking about the git documentation.
Can you believe how funny that is?
So dumb jokes aside, we're talking about the git documentation which you may want to reference at some
point if you have questions or you want to learn more about one of the commands that I'm showing you.
So the docs are accessible at Git Dash Semco.
I never remember that.
I just Google get and then I end up on this web page and then we want to go to documentation pretty
much every time.
That's where I go, you know, I'm not going to about I don't need to see the advantages of get to compare
it to something else.
I'm already using it.
I just want the docs.
Now there are a couple of sections here and most of the time I end up looking at the reference manual.
Occasionally this book called Pro get pretty much never the videos, so the reference manual will start.
There is exactly what it says.
It's a reference manual to all the git commands and main topics.
It is not ordered.
It's not a step by step guide, it's just a reference.
So for example, we've been using get commit.
If I want to learn more about Git commits, I can click on this, I'll zoom in.
It tells us roughly what it does.
Record changes to the repository.
Here's a more detailed description, but then as I scroll down, this is what I end up looking at occasionally
on the docs, all of these options.
So this is one command get commit and we've used one option which is dash m could find that on here
somewhere.
Dash M which is short for dash dash message, use the given message as the commit message.
We already know that.
Hopefully you know how to do that, but here is where we would find that information.
So there are lots of options for every single one of the git commands I've shown you and it's honestly
overwhelming.
I use very few of them, but there are a lot available.
So if you ever have questions about them, if you see somebody use a command, get commit and then the
Dash Z flag and you have no idea what that is, you can read about it here.
Also, if we keep scrolling down, we will find examples.
So there are some examples that show how to use get commit in this example.
But on another page, if we're looking at git log, that will be examples for git log or for some of
the more advanced commands that can be helpful.
And that's pretty much it.
I mean, there's discussion down at the bottom basically for every git command, we deal with this really
thorough but also intimidating set of documentation.
So if you are looking for something more educational or more sort of techy, you can go to the book
and this is grouped into topics that are ordered and it explains things.
So for example, we haven't yet covered branching, but if you wanted to learn more about branching
or if my explanation is insufficient, once you get to that section, you can read more and have diagrams
and sort of step by step explanation here.
And it's pretty I shouldn't say pretty.
It's very well written.
It's a well done book and it is a nice antidote to the dry and purely reference manual documentation.
The book really does have a clear path through it, so I don't necessarily recommend reading the entire
book, but I mean, I come here occasionally when I have questions about things, some commands that
I haven't used in a while or configuring things.
The book is very helpful to explain them.
And then if you just have a one off question about what is that flag or is there a way to do X with
the git log command?
You can go read about it on the reference manual.
Just do your best to stay sane while reading these docs.
There are so many options, so many flags for every single command.
All right, so that's how we get to the docs.
Get them documentation, reference, manual or book.