One of the more common pieces of advice that many a blog article has been written about is to keep your
commits atomic.
So what does that mean?
So what I want to talk about in this video and I'll show you an example.
In this context, the word atomic does not mean having to do with an atom, but rather of something
being irreducible or of a, I guess a base unit, a single component that makes up a larger system.
So if that doesn't mean anything to you, just read the first paragraph here.
When possible, your commits should encompass a single feature, a single change, a fix.
In other words, try and keep each commit focused on a single thing.
And this is important, especially if you're working with code and you're writing code, you're adding
features or fixing bugs.
It's super important to keep things as atomic as possible, to keep each commit focused on one thing.
Again, that does not mean one file.
That means one feature, one thing that you worked on.
So let me show you an example here.
I've got my first novel repository going still, and I'm going to do two things this morning.
First of all, I'm going to add some inspiration, some visual inspiration.
Since I'm such a, I guess, a budding writer, I want to have a little mood board.
So I've actually downloaded a couple of photos that I want to use, just 1920s esque photos.
This is the best I could find with all the copyright restrictions I have to worry about.
So I'm going to make a new folder in here.
I'll just do it through Finder.
I'll call it Mood Board, and then I'm just going to put those images in there.
Okay.
So now I have that folder in there.
And of course, if I type get status, get is going to tell me, hey, there's a whole new directory
mood board that I see but I'm not tracking.
So I keep working on my, my novel and I decide, you know, I'm not sure if I like the name Gatsby.
I think I want to change Gatsby to be Gatsby with a C.
So I'm going to change that across all my files.
How am I going to do that?
Well, with VW's code, it's super simple.
If I go to this little icon here, there's also a shortcut I can never remember.
I can search for Gatsby and I can replace it across all files.
So it found it in four different files.
The characters file, chapter one, chapter two, the outline, and I'll replace it with Gatsby like
that.
And then I can click this button however you do this if you are following along.
I'm just making a change across a bunch of files.
So it's asking me, are you sure you want to replace 18 occurrences across four files?
Sure.
All right.
So now we see it changed here.
Gatsby and the characters file somewhere in here, I'm sure.
Here we go.
But I looked once more for Gatsby.
He had vanished.
So we can trust that it changed across all of those files.
So now I'm ready to start committing.
It's later in the day.
Or maybe I'm going to take a lunch break so I type get status.
And we have a couple of things, right.
We have four files that have been modified, plus a whole new directory that contains a bunch of files
inside all three image files.
So I'm not just going to add all of this to one single commit that breaks this rule or this pattern
of wanting to keep each commit focused on a single thing.
Here, it's very easy for me to break this up and just say, okay, my first commit the order doesn't
really matter, but one commit I'll make will be around changing Gatsby to Gatsby.
That was one thing that I did.
And then the other commit that I'll make will be around adding to my moodboard or creating my Moodboard.
So why don't I start by just adding chapter one?
And chapter two and the characters and outline.
So notice I did not do get add dots because I don't want the mood board.
So now if I type get status, I've got these four things staged for my next commit and now I'm going
to commit.
So get commit.
And those four files, those four changes, they all had to do with changing Gatsby to Gatsby.
So I'd go with Replace Gatsby or how about rename Gatsby to Gatsby?
OC.
I type get status and we still have some uncommitted changes, some stuff I've worked on that get does
not know about.
It's a whole directory.
So this means.
So if I wanted to, I could add specific files from inside of there, get add mood board slash and then
I could type the name of one of those files like Rolls.
It's a Rolls Royce image, so I could do it that way.
Or I can just add the entire directory like this and I'll just add the entire thing.
Now if I type get status, you can see all three image files have been added.
They are going to be committed whenever I commit, so I'll commit.
Now get commit.
M What should I do about start off or create mood board?
Sure.
Create mood board.
Here we go.
So I just made two separate commits instead of one larger commit following this idea.
Keeping our commits atomic.
Breaking them down into some sort of single irreducible unit or piece instead of having like a multipurpose
commit.
That just includes everything you did at once.
Break it down into smaller pieces.
This matters a lot when you're working on code, especially when you're working with a team of people,
and you may need to undo some of the things that you write.
You may introduce a bug at some point, and if you boiled in a whole bunch of changes into one commit
rolling back, that commit could undo a ton of work.
But if you kept your commits atomic single purpose, then if somebody needs to undo one of them, you
don't lose all that other work.
It also makes your code easier to review if you do or when you do code reviews.
It's just generally a practice.
You want to follow group things together in a way that makes sense, keep things small, but don't just
break them up to be as tiny as possible.
Keep them focused on a single thing.