Next up, a quick video on commit messages and which tense, present or past tense you should use while
writing them?
And does it even matter?
This is kind of a weird thing and get it always baffled me when I was starting out.
But the git documentation officially recommends that you use present tense imperative style commit messages.
So present tense meaning verbs like make something or change x fix x instead of past tense fixed changed
updated.
So imperative style though or the imperative mood is best illustrated probably by the quote from the
documentation.
Describe your changes in imperative mood.
Make Zizzi do frosts instead of makes zizzi do frost's or I changed zizzi to do Frost's right things
as if you're giving orders to the code base to change its behavior.
Personally, I always found this weird.
I still do.
Even if I follow this a lot of the time, it just doesn't seem natural to me.
You don't have to do this.
Of course, this is all just convention, just a practice you can get in the habit of.
There's a lot of debate over this, but again, this is sort of the official recommendation from the
Get Docs.
Here's a blog post written by Eumir Gaspar where he talks about the two.
Well, I guess there's more than two options, but the two common options using the present tense or
the past tense and the present tense, as we've already talked about, is what get recommends.
And one of the main reasons people use it is that it actually generates its own messages.
At some point when we talk about merging, it will generate a commit message that looks like this merge,
pull, request, blah blah blah.
So it says merge in present tense.
But honestly, in my opinion I kind of feel like past tense makes more sense to me because you're making
a commit with the work that you have done.
It's finished, you're committing it.
But honestly, at the end of the day, it doesn't really matter.
As long as you are consistent, or more importantly, as long as you're following the pattern set out
by whatever organization you're working with, if it's a company or an open source project, if everyone
else is doing present tense and they ask you to do present tense, you should do present tense.
So I try and stick with present tense when I'm teaching.
If we type git log the commit messages I have been writing our split exe or rename or create or begin.
So those are present tense imperative, but the community is somewhat split on this.
If you look at this popular StackOverflow post from ten years ago, the top answer says you definitely
should use present tense.
But then the second answer says you should almost always use the past tense.
So that's number one.
And number two directly in conflict.
Anyway, this video is going on longer than it needs to.
I just wanted to make that point that in the real world you'll likely come across present tense, imperative
commit messages.
And as I mentioned, you don't have to follow this pattern, especially in your own personal use.
But if you're working at a company or on an open source project, definitely pay attention to the guidelines
for writing commit messages.