So if you recall when I first introduced Get Commit, I said that you could use this command, get commit
on its own, but I recommended against it for the time being because it will open up the default editor
and that default editor is likely to be VIM, which I'll just demonstrate very quickly so you can see
what that experience is like.
I'm going to come over to my little my first novel project and make a very simple change.
I don't think I have any changes at this moment, but I see a typo right here in my outline, so I'm
just going to fix it.
Nick goes home and sees Cat's B for the first time, so I'm going to save that get status.
Then I'm going to do a git add outline text.
Then I'm going to do get commit without the dash.
Hm.
I'm not going to pass in a message or any of that.
Now let's see what happens when I hit Enter.
Hmm.
Let me fullscreen this so you can get a better picture of what's going on.
This is called vim.
It's an editor.
It's built in to the terminal.
It's very it can be very confusing because I can't just start typing.
It's asking me to enter a commit message.
But if I try typing right now, it's actually not going to type a message.
First, I have to enter what's called the insert mode by typing I.
So if I just hit the letter i.
Now at the bottom left.
Can you see that here?
It says insert.
By the way, this really is not the time to be teaching you vim.
I'm not expecting you to learn it, but if you end up in this situation, I want you to know how to
get out of it.
But we're going to change our default editor so don't don't worry about the actual commands.
So I hit I so that I'm in insert mode and now I can start typing and leave a commit message.
So what did I do?
I fixed a typo.
So fix typo just like that.
All right.
Fix typo in outline, maybe.
Sure.
Now.
How do I get out of here?
Well, it's also confusing.
First, I hit the escape key.
One time to leave insert mode.
Next, I need to leave vim entirely.
And to do that, there's a couple of options.
But I'm going to do colon w and then Q.
Oh, gosh.
So W sent for.
Right.
Q stands for quit.
So this is right.
Basically save these changes and quit vim.
It's very confusing.
Now I'm going to hit enter woo and we made that commit and you can see fix typo and outline if I type
get log fix typo in outline so it looks exactly the same.
It's a commit.
Nothing different.
It's just the way that we made it and passed in that message was a lot worse.
Now there are times where using this message flag, the dash flag, is not going to cut it.
If we need to type a much longer commit message, I mean, you could cram it all into a single line,
but on larger projects and large code bases, open source projects, your commit messages might actually
look something like this multiple lines, maybe paragraphs, bullet points.
So that's not going to cut it.
Just passing it in instead of quotes.
You don't want to be typing something like that in your terminal on a single line.
So we do want to configure this version, get commit so that it opens up an editor where we actually
feel comfortable typing paragraphs where we could type something like this.
And for the majority of students and the majority of developers out there, Vim is not that editor.
So I'd like to use VTS code as my editor.
I've been using it in the course.
No surprise there.
But you can configure get to use any really any editor.
You can use voice code or sublime text or any of the other editors that are out there.
I'll show you how to do that right now.
So if you go to the Git documentation, there's this page called Git Command set up and config is on
the appendix for the book.
I'll just include a link to this if you're curious.
And just like before when we configured our username and the email address for our git configuration,
we can do the same thing for the editor.
So depending on what editor you're using, there's a table here and I'm looking for VS Code which is
right here, Visual Studio code and this is the command I need to type.
So get config will do global so that it applies to every repo, not just the current repo code editor
is what we're configuring and I want it to be code which is the name of VS Code, Visual Studio code.
And then I'll talk about this dash dash weight in a moment.
But basically we just copy this line.
So if you're using Sublime, copy this line on a mac or if you're on a PC, copy this line if you're
using something else.
Text edit on a mac.
This is the line, but I'm going to use vs code.
So now I'll head over to my terminal.
I'll paste this in here.
We don't see anything change, but now let's make another commit.
What could we do that won't take too much time?
Okay, here's a simple one.
I have some extra white space in chapter two, just at the top, so I'm just going to get rid of that
and save and now type get status.
All right.
It says I modified that file.
All I did was delete some empty lines, but that's still a modification.
So I'm going to add that get add chapter to text.
Now, I would usually just use get commit dash because it's really just a simple message.
We did something so simple.
There's no point in typing a paragraph, right?
You want to keep your messages as short as possible, but there are times where you need more information.
This is not really one, but I'm going to do just get commit without the dash flag just to demonstrate
that hopefully our editor is configured to be vs code.
Hmm.
Let's see.
There's a problem with the editor code dash dash weight.
So this is a problem stemming from the fact that my terminal does not know what code the command code
is referring to.
So what it's telling me here, command not found.
Basically if I go into vs code I can fix that.
I'm going to open the command palette which is command shift p.
And then I'm going to type code and I want this install code command in path.
Okay so it says show command code succesfully installed in path.
So now hopefully this works.
It knows what the command code is referring to.
So let's try committing again.
Aha.
Now it's opened up in VTS code and you can see over here it's waiting for me to close this file.
So that's why we had to add that dash dash weight right here.
We wanted to wait until we finish editing and save our commit message so I can type my commit in here.
Also, I didn't mention this earlier.
Everything that starts with the hash or the octave character will be ignored.
It's a comment.
It's not included in the commit.
So in here.
What did we just do?
Have already forgotten?
Oh, we removed whitespace from chapter two.
So, you know, remove extra extra whitespace or extra lines in chapter two or something.
Well, it kind of sounds like we actually deleted lines of chapter two.
How about extra blank lines?
Sure.
So now I'm going to save this file.
If that's the message I want.
But I could put a lot more in here and maybe just to demonstrate that I will.
Why don't I just copy one of these example?
Commit messages that I was talking about?
I'm just going to copy this entire thing over.
And this is just to show you that we can do this.
All right.
So here's my much longer commit message.
All these lines, paragraphs of text, some bullet points, they won't be formatted in any particular
way.
I have to do this manually if I want that bullet point.
It's just a dash.
But anyway, this is my commit message here.
Really just the first line that matters.
I'm going to save.
I'm going to close the file.
And then over here.
It now made the commit it was waiting and now it's not.
It finished.
So if I type get log, what do we see.
Oh well we made that commit it is here but it's taking up so much space that's really, really annoying.
So in the next video I'll show you how we can use git log with a small tweak so that we don't have to
see the entire commit message.
In the case of a very long commit message.
Anyway, we set up the editor, we configured it to use VS Code in this video.
If you're doing something else like Sublime text, follow the instructions here.
I'll include this link in the description if you want to check it out.
But you can avoid this for the most part by just using dash em until you really need to type a longer
commit message, which is not all that common when you're starting out.
Once you start working on larger projects, though, it's definitely important to be able to open up
and write messages in an editor.