Next up, totally optional.
Like most of this section just has to do with committing.
I'm going to show you how to make a commit using a gooey like get crackin.
And even if you're not interested in using a gooey, I still think, you know, it's worth checking
out because these guys can help show you your commits.
They help you visualize things.
But also, it's nice to know that, you know, there are different ways of interacting with Git and
at the end of the day we're still just working with that Git folder.
It's just a different interface, a different way of interacting with it.
So I'm using Git Crack in.
I had a whole video on this early on where I talked about how to install it.
It's very simple.
You download it for free and that's kind of it.
And I'm just going to open up this repo that we've been working in my first novel.
So if you have any repo you've created by now, whether it's from an exercise or you're following along,
you have your own novel, whatever it is, we can open it with git cracking.
So here's get cracking.
I'm going to go to open a new repository.
So if you open it up for the first time, it will probably look like this.
It will ask you to open a repository.
And then here is that folder I navigated to.
Sorry, I can't zoom in easily, but I just found my repository.
So that same folder, my first novel and I'm going to open it.
And there we are.
We see my commit history right here.
So right now we're just visualizing the commits.
This is basically what we see with a git log.
Unfortunately, it's not letting me zoom in much more either, but I hope you can see that.
So we have our first one start work on outline and main characters all the way up to remove extra blank
lines in chapter two.
But what I want to show you is how we make a new commit.
So right now, our working tree is clean.
I haven't made any changes at this point.
I haven't diverged for what from what Git has committed, as you can see.
But let's make some changes.
What should we do?
I'm going to add some more to the characters file.
So I just added some information about Myrtle Wilson.
And here's some more information about George Wilson, two characters in The Great Gatsby that come
up in Chapter two.
All right.
So I'm going to save that.
And also, how about I add something to our moodboard?
So I have these images in here.
Let's add another image.
Okay.
So I downloaded two more images, one of alcohol and one of a billboard thematically related in some
way to The Great Gatsby.
They're part of my mood board and both also licensed for me to use.
So I'm going to add those both into this mood board folder.
So I've made a couple of changes and obviously I shouldn't say obviously, but hopefully you're aware
that I could check to see, you know, my status by using Git status and I would see that we modified
characters that text and that there are two new files in mood board which are not being tracked, but
this video is about using the goofy.
If we take a look at the gooey, I get this message.
It says three file changes in working directory so I can click here to view those file changes or I
can just click here where it says Work in progress and I wish I could make this larger.
But what we see is unstaged files, characters that text and then Mood Board, bar and mood board billboard
the two images and you'll see that there's a little icon here with a pencil.
That means I modified or edited that file.
And here, this little plus sign means it's a new file.
So I want to make a commit first.
How about just with the characters changes?
So I want to stage characters, so I'm going to click stage.
So at this point I have staged that one file and actually if I type get status over here, what do we
see changes to be committed characters text.
So it was the same exact thing as me typing get add characters, but instead I clicked stage and then
I'm going to make my commit.
So this first commit is just characters.
So I add my commit message right there or I can type it over here and to my message will be something
like Add Wilson's.
Well since two characters list or.
Yeah, that's fine.
Add the Wilsons.
Maybe the Wilsons.
So added two of them.
All right.
And then I'll commit changes to that one file.
And we see a new commit here.
Add the Wilsons to character list and if I type get status.
We now made it commit.
We don't have this character test staged anymore and if I type get log.
There it is.
Add the Wilsons to characters list.
So let's do a second commit now with the mood board changes.
So I'm going to stage that new bar image and the billboard image, and then I group them together by
staging them and I'll make my commit.
You know, I don't know.
Add.
More.
How about expand?
Add to images to mood board or something like that?
Nothing amazing.
But here's where I write that commit message and here's where I commit.
Before I do that, what do you expect me to see when I type get status?
This is what we typed or what we saw before to untracked files.
But now they're both going to be committed.
They are both staged because I clicked the stage button.
So same process, just a different interface.
I made changes, then I click to stage and I click to commit or I use get add to stage and get commit
to commit.
All righty.
So I'm going to click commit changes to two files.
And there we are.
We have a new commit show up.
And if I do get logged, let's do our one line.
There it is.
Add two images to mood board.
Add the Wilsons to Character List.
So that's just a quick intro to using a tool like Get Cracking.
Of course, the interface changes if you're using a different app like Source Tree or what else is there?
What tower get tower.
There's a couple of them I can't remember.
They all are similar though.
You click to stage and then you click to commit.
You type a message in and this is just a nice educational tool.
Honestly, especially when we get to branching and merging, the diagrams over here are really helpful,
but at this point it's just another way of doing what we already know how to do.