Next up, amending commits.
Occasionally when you're working with Git.
You may create a new commit and then realize just a moment too late that you forgot to include a relevant
file in the commit.
Or another thing that can happen is you make a commit and then you read over the commit message and
you realize too late that you have a typo.
You wrote something wrong in that commit message.
So there are a couple of ways of fixing those problems.
But the easiest one, the one I'm showing in this video, is to amend the commit.
So this allows us to edit or to redo, to update just the previous commit so this doesn't work.
If you made a mistake ten commits ago, this is only if you made a mistake just one commit ago.
So here's how it works when you make a commit here on my slides I'm doing commit m I made some commit.
Then I realized shoot.
I forgot to include a file.
So I add that file, I stage it and then I get commit dash dash, amend and amend is going to redo the
previous commit.
You can read about it on the docs, although as always it's a little bit intimidating.
I'll search for it on here.
Amend replace the tip of the current branch by creating a new commit.
We haven't talked about branches, but creating a new commit.
It's prepared as usual.
The message from the original commit is used as the starting point instead of an empty message.
I don't know if that's at all helpful to read.
I'm just going to show it to you.
So let's go ahead and make a mistake.
I'm going to add a little heading to every file.
So at the top I just wanted to say outline just as an example and then I'll add some space in there,
something like this.
I'm going to do that for all my other files.
Chapter one, two and characters.
So let's do it for characters in here.
So there I have a change in this file.
Here's chapter one or chapter two, rather.
So that's chapter two and then chapter one.
Okay, so I've made those changes, just added a little heading to each one of those files if I type
get status.
Of course, we see we modified four files, so let's go ahead and stage some of these files.
Let's do chapter one.
Let's do chapter two.
I'll make this full screen and let's do the characters file.
But I'm going to deliberately pretend to forget the outline file, so I'll add those three files.
They should be staged.
And normally I would check like I just did with to get status and realize, Oh, I forgot that file,
but let's say I didn't do that and I commit, so get commit.
I'll just do a dash.
Hm.
Commit, add heading to all files or add headings to all files like that.
All righty.
And then I realized, Oh no, I forgot my outline so we can use that amend option that I showed you.
We need to add this file, so we're going to stage it.
Again, this only works if I haven't made another commit.
I can't go back and edit a commit from ten commits ago, but I did just make that commit and I'm going
to amend it.
So I'll add that file, but I'm not going to commit like normal.
I'm going to do a git commit, dash, dash, amend.
All right.
And this is going to open up in V's code because that's what I've configured my editor to be.
And it opens up the previous commit message and this allows me to edit that commit message.
So if I had a typo in here, I could change it.
I could if I misspelled sometimes.
That's the reason for amending.
You might not stage any new files.
You might just want to fix a commit message.
Just get commit dash, dash, amend.
That will open up in whatever editor you've used.
Hopefully you've configured it so that it's not vim or hopefully you know how to use vim.
So I have B's code.
Go back and watch a video where I did that if you need it.
And now I can change the message if needed.
But if I don't want to change the message, I want to leave it, which I do, and I just want to include
that new file or files.
In this case, it's just the outline.
All I need to do is save this file and close it so I'm not going to change the commit at all.
You can see it's also put, modified, outlined text in here that's now going to be included.
I'll close out of there and there we are.
Four files changed is what it said in that commit.
Previously it was just three, but now I amended that commit.
I basically redid it and I included the outline.
All right.
So there's two reasons to do this.
One is to include files, changes that you forgot that you somehow messed up in the previous commit.
The other option is just to redo the commit message, or you could do both of them at the same time.
You just need to add dash dash amend and that allows you to redo the previous commit.