When you're working on a project and you're using Git, there are often situations where you have files,
directories that you just don't want get to know about or to track.
At any point you want them to be completely ignored, and there's a mechanism for doing this.
We can create a particular file called Dot Get Ignore.
But before we go into that, let's talk about why you might want this.
One of the most common situations is if you're working on an application, you're writing code where
you're using API keys, credentials, any sort of application secret that is tied potentially to a credit
card like from us or some API that you're using where you don't want those to get out into the world.
So you put them in a separate file.
And if you push your code up to GitHub, which I realized we haven't talked about, but if you share
that code and you make it public, you don't want that file to be included.
So you'll still have the file yourself locally, but you don't want get to track it.
Other things include operating system files, so on a mac there are these pesky DOS store files.
They have nothing to do with your project or your code.
They just show up in directories, their system, hidden files so you don't want to track those with
git.
There are similar files on windows with a different name, other things, log files or any files that
are output by your application that could easily be generated again.
So if you have an application when you run it, it generates some report every single day and you regenerate
that report on demand.
You really don't need Git to track that and save that report because you can regenerate that report
if that makes sense.
And then lastly, a really common scenario is dependencies or packages.
So if you've ever worked with Node or Python or really any any language and you work with a bunch of
dependencies that you download and install, those do not need to be tracked by git.
That could be hundreds or maybe thousands of different folders and files that you can easily go and
get at any point.
You don't need to bother tracking the dependencies themselves.
So I'm going to show you an example of how we do this.
As I mentioned, the mechanism is through this file with a very particular name.
It's a hidden file that we create, dot, get ignore.
And if we put that really anywhere in a repository, but traditionally we'll put it in the route of
the repository, the top of it, although it doesn't have to be there.
We create a file with that name, get we'll look for that file and inside of it we can tell get what
to ignore so we can put exact file names.
So the first bullet point here is dot ds store git will ignore file with that name.
We can give it folder names by putting a slash at the end and we can also do fancier patterns.
For example, this line here, asterisk, dot log.
This is a wild card that will match anything, I think anything except for a slash.
It will match any character followed by the extension dot log.
So this allows you to tell git ignore all log files.
I don't want to have to write them out.
I don't know what their names will be.
Just anything with dot log.
So I'll just quickly show you some examples.
Again, we haven't really gone into GitHub at all, but on GitHub there are projects and pretty much
every single project here is going to have a dot get ignore file.
And inside we see some of what I talked about RDS store, we see directories like the reports directory
node modules, if you ever work with Node, that's where all the packages are installed.
So we're ignoring that.
Here's another example.
The app signal, if you're familiar with that, get ignore.
There it is.
And there's stuff in here, particular files and folder names.
They're different because this is an Android application versus faker.
I was showing you as a JavaScript app.
Here's TensorFlow, another really popular open source project instead of here get ignore, right?
And then we see similar stuff.
But now some python specific files and folders that they're telling get to always ignore.
So I'm going to demonstrate this and to do this, I'm actually going to make a new repository.
It doesn't really make sense to ignore things in my novel.
Maybe it does, but I'm just going to make a new demo and make a simple node application so I'm not
in a git repository now I'm going to make a directory.
I'll just call this git ignore demo, I'll seed in there, I'll type get status.
Och good.
It's not one yet, but now I'm going to initialize get a net and I'm going to run NPM in it so that
I can use some node packages in here.
So if you're not familiar with Node, it really doesn't matter at this point.
I'm just going to install some stuff and I'm going to ignore it.
But you can ignore any other files using the same stuff that I'm going to show you.
So.
I'm going to make a file.
I'll pretend to write a basic JavaScript app in here.
Index js.
Maybe I'll make a secret file as well.
Secrets dot.
I'll make it a text file and then I open it up in my text editor.
Let's put some stuff in here.
So my index.
JS I'm just going to write some very basic JavaScript code like console.log.
Hello.
Hello world.
All right, so whatever.
This is my application code, then I'll have some secret like API key equals.
Just say that's some secret key I don't want anyone to know about, but I need it for my app.
And then let's go ahead and make our first commit.
So it would be nice if I could make it commit and just do get add dot.
But I can't because that will include secrets text.
So I need to add the index first and then I'll also add my package JSON.
It's just a generated file from Node and then I'll commit start project or something.
It doesn't matter what.
Okay.
And of course, we still have this file that's untracked and we wanted to stay that way.
We don't want it to be tracked.
So if I do some more work in here, I'm just going to copy that a couple of times.
We'll pretend I just wrote a lot of code.
Then I'm going to head over here again to my terminal and I need to add that change.
But I can't do it at DOT.
I need to add just the index.
JS Right, and then I can commit again, you know, add new feature.
This is a horrible commit message, but pretend it's not.
All right.
So now I'm going to go in install something with NPM.
I'll install React.
I'm using NPM in here and we can see I have a new directory node modules and it has react in there and
some of react dependencies.
So if I type get status now it also notices that node modules now exists and my secrets file is still
there.
There's this thing called package lock JSON.
The package JSON is modified, which I'm cool with.
I want to track that.
That's where the dependencies are listed.
So it tells anybody who gets this code I need react, but we don't actually need to track the folder
that includes React.
We can always go get that whenever necessary.
So now let's add in our get ignore file so that this will be ignored.
I'm going to make a new file.
I can do it from here.
I'll just do it from the command line, I guess to be consistent touch dot, get ignore.
And as I mentioned, it's conventional to put it in the route of your project directory.
So now I have that file and then in here I can write certain files and patterns that I want to be ignored.
So, for example, I don't know if there's a store file in here.
No, there's not at the moment, but I don't know why it pops up, but sometimes it just does.
So I'm saying ignore that.
Please also ignore the exact file secrets text.
That's the name of the file and the node modules directory.
So I need a slash.
If it's just node modules like this, it thinks it's a file.
This tells git it's a directory node modules.
So over here if I type get status now.
Whoa, look at that.
Very different now we no longer see.
Well, I got rid of it.
Unfortunately, I cleared, but earlier it was tracking node modules and secrets.
Now we just c get ignore because we did change that file and it exists.
We want to track the get ignore file.
Then also this package locked json and that's fine to track with git.
So now I can just do things like get add dot if I wanted to and I can commit and then I can make some
commit message.
In this case it doesn't really matter.
I haven't done any work, but I'll just say add get ignore file.
And now any time I make changes in those files, if I change my secrets file right there, I'll do something
else in here.
It's just add on to that key I save normally get would notice, but now it says nothing.
It's ignoring this file entirely.
So there's a lot to write and get ignored, especially for complicated projects.
You can have all sorts of stuff in there and to help out.
There are tools online.
Show you one quickly.
This is on the GitHub documentation.
They recommend this one site get ignored.
IO, where you can specify what you're working in.
For example, if you're working on a Python app.
This is a recommended starting place for get ignore and you may not have files with all of these patterns
or these extensions for these directory names, but they're common enough that you can just include
it.
It's really not adding a lot of overhead to your application and they have similar get ignored templates
for JavaScript and pretty much any other thing you can think of.
So that's an intro to get ignore files.
There's a lot to them, right?
The patterns you can write can actually go on the get docs and read about it.
There's more that we didn't even go into.
For example, two stars is different from one star.
A question mark is a way to match a single character.
If you're familiar with regular expressions notation, it's kind of similar here.
But anyway, most of the time it's good enough to just be able to ignore file names, directories and
file extensions using the wild card.
So that's get ignore.