All right.
So hopefully you now have get installed.
We're now moving on to what is probably the most essential section in this course.
We're talking about some of the core get commands.
So there's going to be a lot in the critical column here.
First, we're going to talk about this this concept of git repositories, repos for short, what are
they?
And then we'll learn a bunch of commands, get init.
That's going to be critical and kit status.
These are things you'll use non stop if you use git understanding the dot get folder I'll say is important
but not a critical thing.
You could go your whole life as a get user without really understanding it and what's inside of it.
The committing workflow, a very important concept, sort of an overview that we'll do and then we'll
dive into three more commands get, add, get commit and get log.
None of them are terribly difficult or anything like that, but they are very, very important, essential
to working with Git and they'll come up throughout the rest of the course.
So take your time with this section.
Don't speed through it.
Remember how much is in the critical column because for future sections, that really won't be the case.
So let's go ahead and get started.
What really matters?
Pretty much everything.
Okay, here we go.