All right.
So as the slide says, it's time for a quick, high level conceptual overview.
I'd like to try and introduce things at a conceptual level first before we dive into the commands.
But I also don't want to take too long.
I know we just want to get to the commands.
So in this video I want to talk about the term repository.
This comes up all the time when we talk about Git and GitHub.
So much, in fact that people usually just say repo instead of repository.
Save a couple of characters there that are the same thing.
So a git repository is just a git workspace installing git on our machine.
It's great.
You know, I have git over here.
Hopefully you install get following the instructions in the course I have git.
I can just verify it's here.
I can check the version.
Sure.
But that doesn't mean git is active or that I'm using git.
It's just on my machine.
I have to manually tell Git when I want to use it and in which directories I have to create repositories.
So any time I want to use git for let's say I'm writing a new symphony or a novel or I'm working on
a freelance web development project or whatever it is I need to tell Git to create a new repository.
So it's just a Git workspace with its own history.
So every git repo has its own history.
They're not linked.
They're not connected in any way.
There are these like little encapsulated bubbles.
That's why I have this jar on the right with some git history inside of it so we can have as many repos
as needed, all with separate histories and contents on our machine.
So I may have a bunch of folders, a bunch of different projects.
Each one of these is a separate project.
If I want to use Git, I have to go into each project folder and create a git repository.
I have to tell get.
All right.
I want a repo in here.
And in here and in here and in here.
And whatever happens in those folders, whatever get commands I run, whatever history I store with
Git, they're completely separate and not connected.
So this allows me to have different histories for a symphony, an app.
I'm cloning, a movie script, I'm writing a startup idea, whatever, a novel portfolio website, you
name it.
I can have as many separate repositories as I need.
And to wrap things up here, I have two separate folders, two different projects on my machine, and
I've created Git repositories in each of them, which I haven't shown you how to do just yet, but I
just want to show you that they have separate histories.
So one project is this large web application, a bunch of files and folders, this other one.
So the first one is called Yelp Camp 2.0.
It's a project from one of my courses.
The other one is just animals.
It's a single folder with one file very straightforward, just a list of animals.
They both have separate git histories.
They are distinct repositories.
I can prove that to you in a couple of ways.
I'll show you in the console here.
You can see all of this history here is associated with this Yelp camp repository.
So lots of stuff.
What that stuff is how I see it.
Don't worry about that.
If I go to the animals directory and I do the same thing a lot less and different history, all the
history is about animals.
Another way to show that to you is through a gooey like get crackin here.
I'm looking at the animals history for this one repository.
You can see there's a decent amount of stuff.
It all has to do with animal stuff.
And if I switch over to a different repository, very different, completely distinct history.
There's collaborators.
It's not just me.
And this is it goes back like a year or more versus this animal.
This one is a lot more recent and obviously focused on animals.
Anyway, we'll learn more about what all this is and how we make these checkpoints and how to use it
and the command line and all that stuff in upcoming videos.
But for now, I just wanted to explain this concept of repositories and just prove to show you some
evidence of different git histories for two different repos.
So that's all there is to this term, this concept of a repository.
It's a get workspace.
And in the next video I'll show you how we create them, how we instantiate a new repo.