Okay.
So now that we know what repositories are in general, let's learn how we instantiate a new repo using
Git.
And before I show you that command, I'm actually going to show you a separate, very simple command
called git status.
Git status will come up again and again in this course and just in your life, if you use Git, it's
a harmless command to just reports back to you the status in your current repository.
The thing is, we don't have any repositories yet, or at least if you're following along, we haven't
made any.
So if I run git status anywhere on my machine, assuming I don't have any repos, I get this message
fatal.
Not a get repository.
It's telling me you're not in a git repo so it's aware of what git is.
It's not giving me like command not found.
It's telling me.
Yeah, I know.
But you're not in a repo versus if I am in a git repo and I run git status, we see something different.
Now what we see varies and that's why we use git status.
It reports back to us and gives us information on the current repo we're in.
So we'll use it all the time, but for now it's just proof that we're not in a repo.
But now we're going to learn our second command which is git init.
So this will initialize a new repository wherever we are in our terminal.
So whatever directory I'm inside of will become the home of a new git repository.
So it's the equivalent of what this slide showed or these diagrams where we have some folder and we
initialize a repo inside of those folders, we navigate to the folder.
So in my case, I have an empty folder called Basics.
I'll have different folders for different parts of the course.
I'm going to make a new directory, let's say I'm writing a novel, so I'm going to go with my first
novel and then I'm going to navigate into there.
This is where I want my git repository.
Repository.
I want to have a new repo in my first novel so I can track the history, you know, the drafts, the
changes I make, all of that stuff inside of this project and then I'm going to run, get and knit before
that.
Just to remind you, currently not a repository when I ran that command to get status now I run git
init and it tells me it initialized an empty git repository in and then it gives me the whole path to
where I am.
My first novel.
Now I don't see anything here.
We'll talk about what actually happens in the next video.
There is something here.
It's hidden and it's where git is stored.
But before that, I just want to recap what we've seen so far.
The command get init will instantiate a new git repository for us wherever we are, whatever directory
we're currently in in our terminal where we run that command also.
This is something we run one time per project so we're not constantly initializing if we're working
on the same project day after day.
If I'm working on this novel for a couple of months or years, if more like my speed probably occurs,
we would run git init one time.
Get init just enables git in this one project and then we just use that same repository day after day.
That's kind of the point.
We want that continued history anyway.
Now if I run git status.
We see something different.
So before not in a repository.
Then we initialize get in it.
Now get status.
Gives me something else.
There's a lot of stuff in here we don't know about at this point in time, but we'll make sense of it
soon.
But it's just proof that something git ish is happening, right instead of this message, not a git
repo.
Next up, we're going to talk about what actually happens when I run git in it.
Where is the git folder or files or what information does it create?
I don't see anything.