All right, so we just initialized our first git repository.
Again, that's something we do one time per project, one time per repo.
But what actually happened?
Where is the git in this folder?
Well, I'm also going to show you the docs here as a way of explaining this.
If we go to the git docs, which is git zmcl, I think I've already said I never remember that I just
google git.
And then if you go to documentation and then reference manual, you'll see some get commands including
the one we just used init right there.
And then it tells us get in.
It creates an empty git repository or re initialize an existing one.
But we really care about that first part.
And you'll notice this about the docs.
They're very thorough and often can be kind of confusing at times.
There's just so much information and it's not it's not necessarily displayed in the the friendliest
manner.
Anyway, if we read the description, it says this command creates an empty git repo, basically a dot
git directory with subdirectories for blah blah blah blah blah.
So it creates a directory called dot git.
Now if we know anything about hidden folders and hidden files, you'll know they all start with a dot
and there is a hidden folder that we're just not seeing in this directory where I can get init if i
type non case ls.
I don't see anything but if I use the dash a flag that's one way of seeing all I think it's I don't
know if it's a for all that's what I tell myself.
All files hidden and non hidden.
Now we see this folder.
Dot get.
So if I wanted to, I could look at that.
We don't need to touch it or do anything in there, but this is what we just initialized.
So if I delete this, my git history is gone.
Now we can back it up and put it on GitHub and stuff like that once we get there.
But for now, just to prove this, I'm just going to back out of here.
I Typekit status as we already have seen.
It tells me get stuff.
I'm in a repo.
If I back out one more level, just to be clear.
Now I'm I'm outside of this folder.
If I run git status, not a git repo.
Go back into my first novel, get status.
Okay.
So if I remove that folder rmd ref, you don't need to do this.
This is going to delete the entire get history for this project if I do that.
I typed get status.
I'm back to not being in a repository.
So that get folder is where all the get stuff occurs.
That's, that's what holds it all.
So I'm going to run get it again, which is it's okay here because we didn't have any history, but
we would have lost a whole bunch of stuff potentially if I did have history and I deleted that directory.
So there's a reason it's hidden.
So you don't you don't screw with it.
So that's all I wanted to show you here.
That folder will be located in every git repository you initialize.
Here's this Yelp camp project where I have git.
This is an existing project.
If I do an LZ dash a there we are dot git.
And if I just take a look at that, there's a lot more stuff in this git folder than we had in our Git
folder because I've been using Git on this project here.
We just initialize this and we hadn't really done anything anyway.
In the next video, I'm going to talk about a common problem that people run into beginners with git
run into when they're starting out new repos and then we'll start learning the basics of adding and
committing.