In this video, we'll cover the gift ad command, which is the first of two commands that we'll use
to make a commit.
And as we previously talked about in the last video, we use two commands because that allows us to
separate out particular changes we've made.
We can I think I used the imagery of tweezers.
We can tweeze them out and select them before we make a commit so we can group things together.
And this get ad command is what enables that to happen.
So once we've done some work, we've actually made changes.
We then call those changes out using the get ad command to stage them for a commit and then we can make
a commit.
And in this video we're focusing on the first piece.
And before we can do anything with Git, we need to make some changes.
We need to do that first part, work on stuff.
So I'm going to do a quick demo.
I made this folder, my first novel.
I'm pretending I'm writing a novel.
We have a git repository in here as we did it.
We initialized it earlier.
So I'm now pretending to sit down day one of writing my novel and I'm going to do some work.
And if I was actually writing a novel, I would probably start by making an outline.
That's just how I like to work.
I outline all my courses, so I just made a new file there outline txt and I've opened this folder up
in a text editor I'm using vs code.
So here it is.
It's just an empty file.
So if I'm writing my novel, I'll put some basic stuff in here.
I am pretending that I'm writing The Great Gatsby just so we're up front about that.
It's now in the public domain in 2021.
So yep, I'm writing The Great Gatsby, so I'm going to be writing part of Chapter one.
So I start the outline.
All I know is so far it's very early on in the writing process is that we're going to meet some of our
characters in chapter one.
I haven't figured out what else happens yet, so I'll save that file and if I come over here and I type
get status, we now have made some changes in this project and get notices.
Something it says, something it didn't say earlier.
Untracked files, outline, text.
Hmm.
All right, so I'm still writing.
It's a little bit later in the morning, I've outlined, you know, I need to meet these characters
or introduce them in chapter one.
Maybe I want to start by actually fleshing out those characters.
I'm going to make a file called Characters Text.
So before I actually write chapter one, I want to make sure I've hammered out the details about those
characters, and I'm just going to copy and paste some stuff in I've written.
Okay, so we've got Jay Gatsby, Nick Carraway, Daisy Buchanan, Tom Buchanan, just a little bios
about each character.
And if you're following along, you can put whatever you want in here, and then I save the file.
All right, so I'm done for the morning.
I want to take a break before I actually begin writing chapter one.
So I've saved those files, and if I head back over to my terminal and I type git status again, now
get tells me there's two files that it's aware of, but it's not tracking.
So we've done step one.
I've worked on stuff.
Now I want to make it commit with what I've done.
Well, now we need to talk about a tiny bit of terminology.
Three different locations are not actual physical locations, working directory, staging area and the
repository.
Let's start with this first one working directory.
That's just a fancy way of referring to the directory, the place we're actually working on our project.
So for me, my working directory is this my first novel folder.
And in our working directory I have two files at the moment.
I might have more, I could have 100 files in here.
The working directory just refers to this directory where I'm working.
Then we have the repository itself.
This is the dot git folder.
Remember there is a dot get folder here ls dash a there it is inside of that folder.
At the moment there's some stuff that's just there, some default contents.
But once I actually make a commit, get commit changes, what is in it?
It actually adds new commits to that folder.
So when we actually make a commit, we are updating that folder, the actual git repository.
Otherwise, everything I've done so far is just in the working directory.
And then there's this intermediate thing, this zone again, not a physical location, the staging area,
and this is where we add our changes to before we make a commit.
So here's another flavor of diagram.
We have those three terms working directory, staging area and repository on the left side.
In the working directory you can see a bunch of changes that I've made.
So hypothetically, I've been working for a while, I've done some, I'm working on a project, some
web development project, and I've changed seven files and get has noticed that.
So I've decided, okay, there's actually two discrete things I was working on and I'm going to make
my first commit with those bottom four files that I changed.
They have to do with the nav bar I up.
Dated the Nafaa or I created a new nav bar on our web page.
So I stage those changes first and I do that using the get ad command.
Then I can make a commit.
And then same thing for these other changes I can stage them.
Then I make a commit, at which point I'm actually updating the git folder.
So I know I'm kind of beating a dead horse, but this is really important to command's get add is just
going to stage changes so that I then commit them and this get add command is pretty simple.
It's git space add and then one or more files, the name of a file that we've changed and we can do
more.
We can do multiple if we separate them by spaces.
Otherwise we can just do get add file name.
So over here in my working directory, I have these two files.
Right?
I've changed them.
They exist.
They didn't exist earlier and get noticed.
And it tells me this.
Let me make this full screen here.
It says untracked files characters and outline txt use get add file to include in what will be committed
OC So why don't we do that?
I'll add the first one, so get ADD and I can do autocomplete if I type something and then hit tab.
So get add characters to txt.
Now let's type get status again.
I haven't made it commit.
All that I've done is stage the one file characters text to be committed, but it's not yet committed.
So if I wanted to I could make a commit now with just that one file that I changed.
But I'm going to group them together because, you know, I worked on them together.
They have to do with one another.
Unlike this example here where I wanted to group things into two individual commits, I instead want
to group everything on this project.
So far, just two files into one commit.
So I'm going to also add outline text and then I'm going to look at get status.
We always use get status.
It can never hurt anything, just reports back and you'll see whenever we make a commit those two files
will be included.
So what we need to do next is cover, get, commit.
We need to learn how to make those commits.