So now that we've made it through our first comment, let's repeat the process and hopefully speed it
up.
We'll do some work, we'll add some changes, and then we'll make a commit.
So it's day two of writing my novel, or maybe it's the afternoon of day one and I've come back from
lunch.
I have my outline.
I've fleshed out the very basic characters, the four characters so far that I've included, and I'm
going to start working on chapter one.
So I'm going to make chapter one just a text file.
I'll just do it from within my text editor, but I could do it from the command line.
It doesn't matter how, and I'm just going to save that file.
Maybe I'll put something in here like chapter one.
Hmm.
I'm not sure what I'm going to write in there.
And of course, if I go over here to my terminal, what do we expect to see when I type get status?
Here.
It's telling me, as we've seen before, that there is an untracked file called Chapter one text.
Also, if I go into any of the other files, like how about characters that text or maybe the outline
and I type something else in here, let's just change a single character.
How about Jordan?
I'm going to make a lowercase j and I'm going to save this file.
If I run get status.
Now we see something new.
It says there's a modified file outlined txt.
It doesn't matter that I just changed the case of a letter.
I did change that file and git has been watching that file.
Unlike chapter one, which is an untracked file outline, it's already been added and committed previously.
So get notes about it and it says, Hey, you modified that file.
So let's say I actually continue to work though I'm not ready to do a commit or anything like that.
What should I do?
I'm going to start on chapter one.
I'm going to just copy some of the text from The Great Gatsby.
This is all available these days online, free and legally.
So I'm just going to take some of this chapter one.
If you really want to follow along, you don't need to, but if you want to, I'll include this link
and then I'm just going to paste this in my chapter one.
Okay.
Simultaneously, I decided I need to do a bit more on the outline, so I'll add some here.
There we go.
There's a bit more work that I've done on the outline to match some of the stuff that I've been working
on in Chapter one so far.
Okay, so I'm going to save both of those files and then I'm going to go over here again to my terminal
type get status and we see basically the same thing.
The files have changed.
I mean, it's not telling me right now what has been modified in this file.
There is a way for us to see exactly what's changed.
But for now, all that it says is something changed, an outline.
So if I'm ready to make a commit, I have to decide, am I going to group those files together?
And I am, because they both had to do with chapter one and the work I did on chapter one.
So I'm going to add outline, text, and I'll do it in one go.
If I separate them by a space, I'll also add chapter one text and now if I type get status, we see
that whenever I do commit next both of these changes.
New file chapter one and the modifying modification of outline.
Both of those will be included in the next commit.
So I'm going to commit get commit.
M What's my message here?
What did I do?
How about begin work on chapter one and type get status quick.
What do you think?
We'll see.
We saw it earlier.
Nothing to commit.
Working tree clean.
Okay.
So the next thing I want to talk about is a command called git log.
And the git log command doesn't do anything.
It's much like git status.
It just retrieves information.
And the information it retrieves to us is a log of the commits for a given repository.
And in this repo we only have two commands.
Now there's a bunch of stuff in here for each commit.
Here is one commits, here is another.
And for each one you can see the author, the dates, those well, the author and the email are things
that you can configure and we did configure early on, so it just uses whatever your local git has configured
for username and email.
Then we have the date and then we have the commit message and then up top this crazy looking thing called
the commit hash we don't need to worry about for now, but definitely we will come back and reference
and then here is the second commit.
So at this point, honestly, git log is just a way for us to demonstrate that when we ran get commit
it did something and that's kind of it for now.
So it's the next morning.
I am very excited.
I know how I want to finish chapter one, so I'm going to start by just adding more to our outline.
There we go.
So I'll save again.
If you're following along, you can just change a single character and Git is going to notice.
Now if I type get status right, it tells us, hey, you modified that file again.
Next up, now that I finished that outline for chapter one, I'm going to go back to the actual file
and finish typing the chapter out, which again, I'm just copying from The Real Great Gatsby.
Okay, so I've got a lot more text in here.
I just took it from The Great Gatsby website and I'm going to save.
And now I finished chapter one, I outlined it, and I'm ready to go through the same steps again and
commit.
So I always start with get status and I'm going to show you one other option for how I can add these
two files simultaneously rather than having to add them by name.
If I do get add followed by a dot, I actually have a slide on this.
Here we are.
Get add dot will stage all changes at once.
So whatever we have unstaged at the moment, they're not going to be committed when I use git add dot
both in this case.
But if I had 50 files that were modified, all 50 would be staged and it can be useful.
But also, if you've worked on a bunch of things and disparate features that aren't necessarily ready
to all be committed at once, it's much better to be surgical when you make your commits.
But for now, I finished chapter one.
The outline had to do with chapter one, so I'll add both.
If I type git status, we can see both of those have been modified and now I'll commit get commit dash
em finish chapter one great type get log just as proof and there it is.
Finished chapter one.
Okay, so then I go to bed and I'm having a real rough time with how long chapter one is, and I'm thinking
about it at night as I'm in bed, I'm like, Oh, I really need to fix that in the next morning.
I need to break this chapter up.
So that's what I decide to do.
I wake up and I move my outline around a bit to reflect my new changes.
I decide that right here I want to split my outline, so I'm going to add chapter two now starts right
here.
So I'm just going to move some content around.
Of course, by doing that and saving the file, I've now dirtied our working tree, meaning that we
have some changes that have not yet been committed.
Then I'll go to the chapter one file.
I'm going to take half of this the second half and cut it out of here.
Save this file, and then I'm going to make a chapter to file chapter two text, and I'm going to paste
that in there and save.
So now I have updated chapter one, I've updated the outline and I've created a new file.
Chapter two If I saved all three files, which I did, and I run, get status, get tells us, hey,
there's three things that changed really.
Two things that it knows for sure.
We're modified and a third untracked file that it's aware of.
Vaguely.
It sees that it exists, but it's not tracking the changes.
So I'm going to add all of them and we can use the same shortcut I showed you get add dot because they
all have to do with the same thing.
It's just the same piece of work.
Something like when I commit, my message will be split.
Chapter one.
Into two pieces or something like that.
Looks good type get status.
Working tree clean and get logged.
We see we have a new commit.