So it's time to get some practice with the concepts and commands I've covered in this section.
So of course you don't have to do any of this, but I highly recommend you do, especially if you're
new to get and you haven't seen any of these commands before.
This is an opportunity for you to get some practice.
It's a simple exercise in terms of the content.
The actual files we'll be working with are based around two shopping lists, so there is a link in the
resources for this video.
I recommend you open it up.
It contains a link to this exact page.
It has the instructions I've typed up.
So there are steps, a step by step set of instructions for what I'd like you to do, starting with
make a new folder called shopping, initialize a new git repo inside of it.
Make sure you're not already in a git repo and then make a new file called yada txt then make a second
file groceries dot txt make a commit that includes both empty files, so a commit with both of those
files.
And then I tell you the exact message you should use.
And if you deviate from that, it's not a big deal.
But anyway, I'm just putting it there if you want to follow that and then make some changes in the
yard txt file we actually add some content and then we add some content to the groceries and you can
just copy and paste from here and then make a second commit, including only the changes from the groceries
file and the message for the commit should say add ingredients for tomato soup, then make a second
commit, including only the changes from the yard file.
And that message should say add items needed for garden box.
And then next up, we're going to make some changes to both files.
We're going to add this line to the end of the yard file and then in the garden file, we're going to
change the quantity.
It did say two bags of potting soil.
We're going to update that to three.
And then once both of those are done, we'll make a commit that includes both of those files.
And then you should use this message.
And then the very last thing is to use some unnamed git commands that we've covered to display all of
those commits and we should see three commits.
So that's a set of instructions, hopefully straightforward, but don't feel bad if you don't remember
the exact commands, right?
You can always reference them.
It's more about making sure you have the conceptual flow down of how you make it commit.
Okay, so I highly recommend you try it and stop the video now because I'm going to just go through
the process myself if you want to watch.
But again, I really strongly, strongly as I can through this pre-recorded video, I recommend that
you try this on your own and then if you get stuck, you can check out the solution.
Okay, so step one create a new folder called shopping and init a repo inside of it.
So I have an empty folder called exercises and I'll make a shopping directory and CD into it.
Make sure it's not in a git repo.
I'm not so I'll run git init to make me that new repo.
Then it says make a new file called yada txt.
So I'll do that from the command line.
Although you don't have to.
But here we are.
Touch yards txt and then make another new file called groceries oc touch groceries txt and then it says
make my first commit.
That includes both empty files and then use this message and I'll just copy that message.
I guess.
So now if I run get status.
There are two files that I currently are not.
My repo is currently not tracking.
So before I can make a commit, I can't make a commit right now.
There's nothing to commit.
I need to stage those files so I'll do a get add groceries and yard.
I can do them separately or just in a single line.
Now I type get status.
Great.
I'll do a git commit because that was the next instruction.
Using this message I copied create yard and groceries lists.
All right, so now I have one commit down.
The next instruction says in the yard file.
Add these two lines, so I'll copy that and I need to open the yard file.
Technically, I could do this from the terminal, but I'm going to use I mean, you could just go to
your text editor and open the terminal or open the file, rather, or I can use the code shortcut if
I'm using vs code and you've configured that code and then I'll just do dot that will open the entire
directory for me in VS code and here it is.
I have my two files.
So in the yard file I'm going to paste this two bags of potting soil, one bag of worm castings, and
then in the groceries file I'm going to copy and paste this and save both of them.
And then it says Make a new commit, including only the changes from the groceries file.
And this is what the message should be.
So we made changes to two files, but we only want these changes in this first command.
So that's the groceries file.
If we do get status, we see both of them have been changed.
I'm going to add I'll clear just to put this up top, get add groceries and that's all I'm going to
add.
So this will be included in the commit and I'll make that commit.
I'll use dash em and just do it from the command line and one go add ingredients for tomato soup.
And now we see that we still have those changes from yard that are not committed.
That's the next piece.
Make a second commit, including only the changes to the yard file and it should have this message.
Add items needed for garden box.
So we'll copy that.
Get add the yard file, get commit dash m.
There we go.
Add items needed for garden box and now we have no uncommitted changes.
And then the next step is to add the following line to the end of the groceries file.
So we need to buy a couple of seed potatoes, just potatoes that I'll buy from the grocery store.
So it goes in the groceries list.
Okay.
And then also I need to update the yard file so that it says three bags of potting soil instead of two.
So there we go.
And of course now if I type get status to files, both of them have been modified.
So now it says make a commit that includes both of those files.
So changes to both files with this message.
Add items needed to grow potatoes OC so I can do a get well.
I don't know why it did another status.
I just did that into a get add and then do both file names or it can do a get add dot to just add everything
which is these two files and then I'll do my get commit, dash em with that message.
And then the last piece, unfortunately I just realized there's a small typo here is to use an unspecified
command that we learned to display a list of all the commits.
This should actually say four because we've made four commits, the first empty one.
That's the one I forgot to count when I made this.
So let me update that very quickly.
That should say four instead of three.
Let's refresh.
And there we are.
You should see four.
Okay, so let's try this.
Let's go over here and the command is git log and I should now see four commits.
Here's the first one.
Create the empty lists.
Here's where I added to the grocery list for tomato soup ingredients.
Here is what I added to the garden or the yard list.
And then here is where I added to both of them.
And that's the end of the exercise.
I hope that you're able to go through that and and not have to follow along with me step by step, although
there's no shame in that either.
You'll get more practice with this throughout the rest of the course.
This is really, really the bread and butter of git add, commit, add, commit.
We do it all day long or at least many times a day.
Okay.