Okay.
So hopefully after the last section you're now familiar with branching and the basic branch commands
like Git branch and get switch.
We're now going to see how we can combine changes between branches, how we can merge branches into
one another.
So very important to understand branches before we can talk about merging them.
This section, there's really not a whole lot of different concepts that we cover.
It all has to do with merging branches and there are a few types of merges.
There's one called a fast forward merge.
I'm going to put that in critical as well as the get merge command that I'm going to show you and the
merge commits or merge commits that are generated from merge.
In some scenarios, it's really the only command I show you in this section.
But the probably the trickiest area is something called merge conflicts and learning how to resolve
them.
So I've put that in yellow.
It's not impossibly difficult or anything like that, but there's just some new things we need to talk
about when we try and merge changes together.
There's conflicts, how do we resolve them?
Get might get angry or might panic.
So how do we fix that situation?
All critical then the one thing that will go in nice to have you could totally skip this.
I show how to use vs code the text editor that I like to use it has some built in functionality to help
us resolve conflicts.
Totally nice to have but you would be fine.
Never seeing that video as well.
So concept wise, there's not all that much going on in this section, but the stuff that is going on
is all critical.
Take your time going through it, follow along, get some practice.
And this is one of those last critical sections where, you know, after this you'll have a foundation
that you need to work with it.
And then everything else that we add on top will be important or nice to have, but not a whole bunch
more critical stuff until we get to GitHub.