So now let's try a fast forward merge which just to recap from 2 minutes ago at the end of the last
video, a fast forward merge is a special case of a merge.
It's a simpler merge to perform.
The commands are the same, but from gets perspective it's really easy because all it has to do is move
a pointer up some number of commits to catch up or to fast forward to some particular destination commit.
So in these diagrams we're fast forwarding master two commits if we merge the bug fixed branch into
master.
So that's what we're going to practice.
We're going to try this out.
Remember that this is a special case of a merge, not all merge this work this way.
And also remember the steps.
The first step is to switch to the destination branch we're merging into.
So back here, if we go with these diagrams, we need to switch over to master.
If we weren't on master already, assuming we want to merge these commits into master, then all we
do is run, get, merge, and then some branch we want to merge into master and then in this case that
will make master catch up on those commits from bug fix.
In other situations, we might have some additional work to do in the event that there's additional
commits on master that don't exist on bug fix or there's conflicting information.
That is what we'll talk about in the next couple of videos.
But for now we're just going to practice with a fast forward merge.
So switch to the branch and then merge some other branch in OC.
So let's try it out.
So over here on our playlist example we have well quite a few branches.
I haven't shown this, but if we use Dash Vee, we get a little bit more information, we get the last
commits, the tip of the branch and the commit message alongside the branch name.
So we started off with our master branch.
It's very simple, right?
If I switch to it, it just has these two AB songs.
We look at git log.
We have two commits there.
And then we have our oldest branch, which I think I'm going to merge into master.
So let me take a look at oldies.
So it has some additional content.
But if we look at git log, it just has the first two commits from master and then it has what, three
more commits on top?
But nothing has happened to the master branch since we split off, since we created this oldest branch.
So this is an example of what would be a fast forward merge.
Just to be clear here, I'm using this distinction.
I'm calling it a fast forward merge, but the commands you use are still just get merged and I'll show
you a merge in the next video.
That is not a fast forward.
It behaves the same way.
We use the same commands.
You'll just see there's an extra hurdle along the way potentially.
Anyway, I want to merge my oldest branch into master so I can get all of this stuff in my master branch.
So we'll go to master, get switch master.
That's the first step.
Once again, I do get log.
We only have two commits.
This is where master leaves off.
This is all that it has.
But now I'm going to run, get merge and then the name of the branch I want to merge in to master.
I'm currently on master.
I want to merge the commit from oldest.
And what did we see?
It says fast forward right there and it tells me one file change, seven insertions, one deletion.
Let's take a look at our playlist file now.
Cool.
We can see that all of this stuff was added in.
And more importantly, if we look at git log, we see that we had the first commits that we always had
on this branch, but now we have these other commits that came from the oldest branch, the George Jones
commit, George Harrison Commit and the Van Morrison commit.
And that is our first successful merge.
We merge the content that commits from oldest on to master.
Now a very important note is that we still have the oldest branch.
It doesn't delete that branch, it's still there.
So I could go back to oldies and do something new and it would not exist on Master.
So they're not forever in sync.
This is one moment where everything from oldest was added on to master, but that doesn't mean that
they're the same and that they'll stay the same if they are.
They're still separate branches and I can do separate work.
They are distinct contexts, but right now the commits from oldest were merged in to master and that's
an example of a fast forward merge where the master branch in our case had to catch up on commits from
a merged branch.