So as I've mentioned a couple of times, not all marriages are fast forward marriages.
I'm going to show you an example of that in this video.
So imagine you're working.
I don't know.
You're on a team, two people and you have your master branch on a project and then you create your
own branch to fix a bug or try some experiment out or whatever it is.
And you're working over there for a few hours and then you're happy with it and you want to merge it
back in to the master branch.
But then you realize, Hey, somebody's already done some work on the master branch.
My teammate, my partner has done work since I created my branch.
So there's a commit over here or maybe ten commits that I don't have on my branch on bug fix but is
on master.
So when I try and merge it's no longer a fast forward.
If I just try and take these two bug fixed branch commits, it's not a matter of just having master
catch up.
Now there's new information that I don't have on bug fix and there's information on bug fix that master
does not have.
So to make this merge happen, it's not terribly complicated or anything.
We use the exact same commands but get may not be able to do it automatically.
For us it depends on the particulars of our commits and if there's conflicting information.
For example, what happens if on the master branch my partner edited line 59 of a file and on the bug
fixed branch I edited the same line to be something else.
Which one wins when there's a conflict?
Well, that's something we're going to address in the next video.
For now, I'm going to show you an example where we don't arrive at a conflict and instead get is able
to make the merge for us automatically.
So what happens in these scenarios when it's not a fast forward merge, something called a merge commit
is generated.
Basically get just makes a commit for us on the branch that we're merging into the recipient branch.
It makes a new commit for us and it will prompt us to include a message.
And one thing I'll just call your attention to really quickly is that this new merge commit is the first
commit we've seen that actually has two different parent commits.
Remember, every commit has a parent.
So if we take this commit here, it has one parent, this one has one parent, this one has this parent
and this parent from bug fix.
So commits can have multiple parent and in fact they do whenever we make a merge commit.
I just want to point that out really quickly.
This is something that will come up later on anyway.
For now let's try making a merge commit so I'll show you this.
However, with our road trip playlist, as great as this repo is, there's quite a few branches going
on and it's kind of difficult to just visually show you with all this other clutter.
So what I'm going to do is just duplicate some of what we've done.
I'm just going to make a new repo really quickly, so I'm going to back out of here.
I'll call it playlist.
Take two.
I'll seed into that, make sure I'm not in a repo.
I'll initialize and then I'm going to make a single file on my master branch.
I'm going to call this song's txt and I'm going to open this up in my editor.
Okay, so here's that file.
I'll add a new commit here, get add songs, text, get commit, add songs file.
All right.
So I'm just going to quickly add two songs in here.
I added two songs by ABBA again.
I've opened this repo and get crackin so you can see.
Master Branch has exactly one commit add songs file.
Now I'll make my commit in here just to show you again.
I can do it visually.
I click stage for that file instead of get ad and then add to ABA songs.
Commit changes to one file.
I'm on the master branch.
Great.
So I'm now going to branch off from this master branch and I'll make a branch called ABA.
Sure.
It's going to include more ABA songs, so I'll go ahead and do that.
I'll do it from here, get branch aba and then I can switch to it, get switched to ABA.
So I'll add another couple ABA songs.
I'll make a commit on this branch.
All right, so I'll do Mama mia by ABA and then I'll stage that file and then add Mama mia and I'll
do one more commit.
What's another song?
I guess?
Dancing queen.
Dancing Queen ABA.
And I'll do the same thing.
Definitely do not need to do this with the guy, but I'm just trying to show it in two different ways.
So add mama mia.
Okay.
So now we have what, two commits on master branch and two commits in addition that are only on the
ABA branch.
So if I were to merge right now, it would just be a fast forward if I merged the APA changes into master.
Master just catches up, but I'm going to go back to master and do some more work.
So this is the same idea that I showed here where what if I'm working on a branch and then a coworker
does a new commit on master in the meantime?
So let's do that.
Let's add a completely new file to master.
Remember I said we can run into conflicts which complicate things.
I'm going to show that in the next video.
So that's why I'm going to do it in a separate file.
I'm going to make a new commit maybe instead of just songs.
I also want a playlist for podcasts, so I'm going to make a podcast file on the master branch.
So podcasts dot txt.
Okay, so now I have this new file and I'll make a commit just to commemorate that.
I'll do it this time from the command line.
So get add podcasts, text, get commit, add podcasts file so back and get cracking.
We see now master has this new commit that ABA does not know about.
ABA knows about these four commits, the two ABA commits plus the two prior on master.
But now master has a new commit and so merging is going to be slightly different.
It's not a fast forward as we've discussed.
I am just going to add one commit to master, maybe one more, go to the podcast file and add something
to the podcast.
So I'll how about some good podcasts?
I like one called the lead a sports podcast.
Radiolab obvious.
Well, I shouldn't say obviously, but a lot of people know that one.
This American Life.
We'll just stop there three podcasts and I'll add the podcast file and commit add three podcasts.
So now on Master, we have two commits that APA doesn't know about, and on ABA we have two commits
that master doesn't know about.
So I'm going to do the merge just like before.
I'm going to merge the ABA branch onto master.
I shouldn't say just like before because we haven't had an ABA branch, but I'm just going to do the
same process where I go to master, I'll switch to master and then I'll merge the ABA branch in to master.
So this is what it looks like right now.
Just keep keep dry on this.
And remember, right, we split off to make ABA and then I kept going on the master branch and I added
the podcast file.
So now I'm on the master branch, right?
Just double check and I'm going to merge ABA.
So get merge aba.
Did I capitalize the branch name.
Yes, I did.
Okay, there we are.
Get merge aba.
Oh, and take a look at this.
It opened up my editor because I've set my default text editor and get to be V's code, and it's waiting
for me to close that file.
Just like when I make a commit.
If I don't use the dash m flag, it opens up V's code.
And so this tells us we have a new commit.
Remember, I talked about this idea of a merge commit being made for us.
That's exactly what's going on.
Get made a commit for me and it suggested a method message merge branch aba.
I can add other stuff in here if I want to.
Usually I just leave this alone because you're just merging the branch and that's pretty self explanatory.
But we could edit this commit message.
All we need to do is close.
So if you did configure your editor just close out and that will make our new commit.
There we are.
It says Merge made by the recursive strategy.
We'll learn more about that.
Well, you can in an appendix a bit where I talk about how it works.
Totally optional, though.
Let's take a look over here and get crackin.
What do we see now?
Well, this line is new.
See that right there?
And a new commit right there that says Merge Branch ABA.
So I can also view this with git log.
I'm on master.
We can see I have the original master commits and then I have the commits from our ABA branch.
By the way, I screwed up.
You probably saw this before me I named.
I gave them the same commit message.
Add Mamma mia!
Add Mamma mia.
Even though one of them was actually adding dancing queen and the other was adding Mamma mia.
Anyway, we have those two and I have my commits from the master branch, add podcast file, add three
podcasts and then I have this merge commit that get made for me and I just left the default message.
So that's an example of a non fast forward merge where things were still automatically merged.
I just had to provide a message.
There was no conflicting changes.
There was no problems that arose.
For example, I wasn't changing two things in the same file.
Git was able to figure out oh it just merge in that new stuff into the actual songs, file this APA
stuff and keep the podcast changes that are on the master branch already.
So that's one example of a merge commit.
In the next video I'll talk about what happens when there is a conflict and how we resolve that.