All right.
So in this video, I'm going to demonstrate generating a merge conflict and then resolving it.
And I'm going to keep working with our simple repository.
Currently it has two branches, Master and ABA, but I'm actually going to delete the ABA branch because
I merged in those changes and let's say I'm done with it, so I'm going to delete it.
There's a couple of ways of doing it.
I've actually already shown this, but basically get Branch Dash DX and then a branch name and you want
to make sure you're not on that branch.
So if I want to delete this ABA branch, I'm not on it.
So get branch, I'll do a full screen dash dx aba and it's gone.
So I had all of the changes merged into Master, so it doesn't warn me.
When I first introduced how to delete a branch, it did warn us because we hadn't learned how to merge
changes in, but now everything is merged in.
I don't need to force this delete with a capital DX.
Okay, so now we have just the master branch.
All right, so now what I'm going to do to demonstrate merge conflicts is I'm going to make two branches
and I'll do it quickly.
I'll probably fast forward through a lot of it, one for our friend Bjorn and another for our friend.
I don't know Serena.
And they're going to each have their own branch where they can make their own playlist for the road
trip, and they're definitely not going to agree.
So they'll make their own playlist on their own branch, and then I'll merge them together when we're
ready for our road trip.
So I'll start by making Serena's branch, so I'll do it in one go get switched dash, see Serena.
And then I'll also go back to master, get switch master and then I'll make the other branch get switched.
Dash See for Bjorn.
All right, so now we have two branches.
Well, we have three, but we have two that we just made Serena and Bjorn, and they're all referring
to the same spot that master currently is.
So now we're going to switch over.
Let's we're on Bjorn.
So let's just work on Bjorn's branch.
Bjorn really does not like Abba that much, but he likes Dancing Queen, so he's going to keep Dancing
Queen.
Then we're going to add some music in that Bjorn does.
Like Bjorn likes a band called King Gizzard and The Lizard Wizard.
So he adds that in.
We'll make it commit for him or he makes a commit.
I'll just do it here.
Stage all changes and I'm just going to do King Gizzard Lizard Wizard Song.
All right.
So we're on The Bjorn.
Branch, and he adds One more song.
What should he do here?
He likes The Strokes, so he adds both or two songs in By The Strokes OC.
He stages them, he commits Add to Strokes songs.
Then simultaneously, Serena is working on her branch and she likes Abba quite a bit.
She even goes as far as to add another Abba song in, she adds.
What is it?
Gimme, gimme, I think by Abba.
So she makes that commit.
Stages her change.
Add one ABBA song.
Okay.
And she does one more change.
What else does she like?
She likes Dolly Parton.
So she adds, Here you come again.
So she adds that change.
She stages it.
She commits add one Dolly Parton song.
Okay.
So now when we take a look, if we ignore everything that we did earlier, we just look from here and
above, we can see that we have two branches we're ignoring master.
We have Serena and we have Bjorn.
And Serena has two commits that don't exist on Bjorn, and Bjorn has two commits that don't exist on
Serena.
But unlike the previous merge we did where we were merging this ABBA branch with the master branch,
there were no conflicts there.
Here, there are definitely conflicts because we're editing the same file and some of the same lines.
So when I switch right, I'll switch one more time from Serena now to Bjorn.
We can see there's a lot of changes going on in there.
So when I try and merge the two, we're going to run into an issue.
So now I have to decide where I want to do the merging.
Do I want them to still have separate branches and just continue to have separate branches?
If so, maybe I'll make a third branch.
I'll call that one.
What should it be?
Get switched c combination or just combo?
And I'm branching from Bjorn.
That's where I am now.
So it will include all the stuff from Bjorn and then I can merge in the changes from Serena OC.
So now I have this new combo branch, it's at the same spot as Bjorn.
They're referencing the same commit.
Now I'm going to merge in Serena, so here we are.
I'm on combo which contains the same stuff as the Bjorn branch I'm going to do get merge so Rina and
here we go it tries to auto merge nope conflict merge conflict in songs text automatic merge failed
fix conflicts and then commit the result.
So we go to our editor.
I'm using vs code.
You can see it does some nice highlighting for me and we have those markers I mentioned so you can see
head right here from that line down to here those equal sign.
This is what we had on the branch originally.
In our case it was the combo branch so we can see it.
It's Bjorn's changes and then here this is the change or the changes we had coming in from the Serena
branch.
And I have to decide, do I want just Serena stuff?
Do I want Jess Bjorn's?
No, I want both.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to delete these markers.
We get rid of those.
So all of that.
And then I'm going to keep, you know, where they have overlap.
For example, Dancing Queen is on both of them.
I don't want Dancing Queen twice, so I'm going to do that.
And otherwise I think everything is unique.
The point is, it's up to me.
It's totally up to me what I want to keep and don't keep.
And in this case, I mean, if we're doing a playlist to friends, I guess it's fair, it's equitable
to allow them both just take both of their songs and combine them.
But if I wanted to, I could say, You know what, I only like Serena songs.
I'm getting rid of you, Bjorn.
And I could do that.
I could just get rid of that and say, This is what we're going with, but I'm not going to I'm going
to keep both of their songs in there and I just remove the duplicate which was Dancing Queen.
So now I save.
So go back to this guide here.
First step, open the files.
Second, edit the files.
Third, remove the conflict markers.
We did that.
Fourth, add changes and make a commit.
So whoops, I need to go back to my terminal.
We type get status and it tells us we're on this branch combo on merged paths and it tells us this songs
that text file has been modified so now we just add the changes.
Okay.
And then we commit, get, commit and we can just do something like resolve conflicts or.
It's up to you really.
But I'll just do resolve conflicts to keep it short and simple.
And that's what this commit is.
This commit is us merging and resolving those conflicts.
So now let's head over to our little visualization here.
It looks exactly the same as what we had earlier.
It's the same process, right?
We merged this branch, Serena, into combo and we have this new merge commit.
The difference is that we had to do some work to make that commit.
We didn't just approve a commit message like we did a couple of videos ago.
Instead, we actually had to dig into a file and make some changes.
We had to look at those markers that get adds for us, these things, and figure out what we wanted
to keep from the two branches and then make changes save and then add and commit.
But now that conflict has been resolved and we're on our new branch combo, which includes the commits
that it had earlier from Bjorn and the new commits from Serena and the conflicts there that we manually
resolved.