All right.
So next up, I'd like to show another example of resolving conflicts.
But this time I'm going to show you how to do it using VTS code.
So VTS code has some nice built in functionality to help you resolve conflicts or it can help in some
scenarios.
So I'm just going to come up with another situation that will cause a merge conflict.
What I'm going to do is go to my master branch, which I'm currently on.
We'll ignore the combo, the Serena, the Bjorn branches.
For now, I'm going to go to the master branch and I'm going to make a new branch from here.
So currently on Master, we just have four songs and three podcasts in the podcast file, so I'm going
to make a new branch.
Let's do get switch.
You know what?
Why don't I just to be different, I'll use git checkout, dash b if you remember, this is another
way of making a branch and switching to it.
It's the old way of doing it before get switch.
It's Dash B to make the branch and switch to it.
It's kind of confusing.
The alternative is get switch dash c.
Anyway, I might be screwing you over by mixing and matching them.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm.
I'm telling myself it's better to expose you to them so that you see the different options.
But maybe it's just confusing.
I apologize.
Anyway, this branch is going to be called.
How about, I don't know, silence?
Okay.
So get check out Dash be silence and this playlist.
The person who wants silence.
They're going to go to their playlist and remove everything.
All songs and all podcasts like that.
And they're going to add and commit.
So get add.
Let's just add dot get commit.
Empty podcasts and songs files.
All right, so that's our first half, right?
We have our branch silence that we basically just emptied everything out of.
We still have the files.
So then I'm going to switch back to Master, get switch master and what should we do?
Let's add a podcast.
So the lead Radiolab, This American Life one I like recently is Recipe Club and another one is Broken
Record, a great music podcast, and then we'll add a song in here.
Should we do another Abba song about Waterloo by ABBA?
All right, so I'm going to add and commit those get add dot, get commit.
Let's just go with, I don't know something generic add podcasts and songs.
It's not a very it's not a good commit message at all, but just keeping it quick and simple.
Okay, so this is where we stand now on my master branch.
I have this new commit add podcast in songs.
Right?
I added this right here, Waterloo by ABBA and these two podcasts.
But before I did that, I branched off and that's where we created our branch called Silence.
And on the Silence Branch, I did one thing and one thing only, which was I emptied out those two files.
So I have a new commit on silence and I have a new commit on master.
I'm going to try and merge them and as we know, that should generate a conflict because it's not as
simple as a fast forward and get can't figure out automatically how to merge these because we edited
this podcast file both on this branch and on the Silence branch and we did the same thing for the songs
file.
So if I want to merge in the Silence branch to master, I'll check get status.
Okay we're good to go get merge silence.
And now we have an example where we have two files with conflicts.
So that's another thing I wanted to demonstrate.
You're not always just going to get one file.
Sometimes you can get a whole bunch of files, especially if, well, we can address that later.
If things have gone wrong or you're you're not really getting your coworkers code as frequently as you
should.
Let's say you do a whole bunch of work for like a year, and then you come back to the office and you
try and merge things into master.
It's not going to go well anyway.
Two files with conflicts, songs and podcasts.
Automatic Merge failed, fix them and then add and commit.
So I wanted to show how to do this with VS code where there's a built in interface.
So most editors, code editors have some support for this.
This is really nice if you have to resolve conflicts, we don't have to manually go and delete everything,
right?
If I if I want to accept silence, if that's what I want on this branch, I merge in the changes from
silence and I want the silence version.
So the empty files I can click accept incoming change.
This is the incoming change or I can accept the current change.
What we already have on Master or I can accept both changes which is not going to look like anything
because silence, as you can see, there's nothing here.
We deleted it right on that branch.
We committed an empty file.
So in each of these files where there's a conflict, I could go about it manually, delete these markers
myself, choose what I want, or I can just accept incoming change.
So it does it for me.
Not that impressive because it just deletes what was in there, but that's only because our incoming
branch was empty in this file.
So I could do that.
Or if I wanted to, I can put anything in here.
Just I can add changes in here.
Silence and save that and add and commit.
It's totally up to me.
I'm not limited to just either or.
Sometimes when you're resolving conflicts, you may need to go in and add additional code or a comment
to explain something.
So it's not always just a binary, this one, that one.
Sometimes there's a bit of a grey area, so I'm going to accept the incoming change again.
Or maybe I'll just show you if you click Accept Current Change.
We end up with what we currently had on Master, but I'm going to delete that.
We've now gone to silence in both of them.
We merged in those changes that was coming from our Silence branch.
And now I can go over to my terminal.
Oh, by the way, here, the guy also shows me that there's conflicts, and specifically it will even
show me where the conflicts are, and I guess I can resolve them here.
I've never used get cracking to do that, but it's kind of cool.
Anyway, I'm going to go to my terminal and get status.
We have those two files we modified, so I'm going to add them and get commit and just do something
like merge silence branch.
And there we go.
Now we take a look at the guy and we can see we merge that silence branch into master.
And with that merge it doesn't look like much because our files are both empty.
But that did indeed come from the Silence branch.
We still have this whole history on Master, a whole bunch of commits that came before it.
You can see that with git log, write all these commits and then we have merge silence branch and we
can see empty podcasts and songs files.
That is the commit that came from the Silence branch right there.
So that's just another example of resolving conflicts.
In this case, we had two files that we resolved.
You can have, I mean, as many as there are.
There's no limit on that.
And we fix them all in the same way.
You open each one up, figure out what you want to keep, keep the incoming branch changes, the current
branch changes or both.
Save your files and then make that new commit to merge them OC.