Before we talk about the ways we can use get dif the different variations the options let's discuss
the output.
So the output that we get from get diff, whatever the diff is that we're trying to generate, it always
follows a very similar pattern and it looks something like this.
You can see over here on the right, it's kind of crazy looking.
I mean, we see hopefully relatively clearly some of the code or changes in a file, but then there's
a bunch of stuff before we've got pluses.
We also have minuses, we have weird looking symbols.
He's at ATS, so let's walk through what exactly is going on.
So for these diagrams, I'm using a very simple example of a repository where we have a file called
Rainbow txt and I made a commit.
It looked like this.
Red, orange, yellow, green, blue, purple.
That's how I learned the rainbow when I was a little kid.
It was just blue and purple at the end.
But then we make some new changes.
We haven't committed anything, but I made some changes in the working directory in the same file and
I updated it to be Blue Indigo Violet Roy G Biv OC.
So clearly we can see it's a minor difference.
We changed the same file so that purple is gone.
We deleted that and we added indigo and violet.
So when I run the git diff command and again I'll walk through doing that in the different variations,
but I'll get an output that looks something like this.
So there's a lot of stuff going on even just for that tiny little bit of a change.
Hopefully you can see, right, we see purple in red with a minus sign, indigo and violet in green
with a plus sign.
But let's talk about what we actually see on this diff on this output.
So the first thing up top, it's going to say diff and then dash, dash, get, but then it's going
to have the files that are being compared.
Usually these are actually going to be the same file, just two versions, the old version of Rainbow
and the new version, right?
The version from the last Commit in the version in my working directory.
But it could be different files.
You would have to set that up yourself.
Typically it's the same file just over time between commits, between branches, between your staging
area and your working directory.
It's the same file typically, so Git is going to call one A and the other one B, so you can see Rainbow
text.
The first one here is going to be a rainbow that text.
The second one will be B, so we may get an output that's a lot more complicated, but there's always
going to be the first line, the files that are being compared to files.
So helpers s compared to helpers tasks.
And here's what changed in that file and here's another file.
Main CSS, main CSS.
So if I just rerun the command that I had earlier, we can see it's telling me here is the diff between
index HTML and index HTML and then I keep going down.
Now we have a different file.
Griggs and Griggs if I keep going down, here's another file.
Main CSS.
Okay, so it's just telling us the two files.
Usually they're the same file over time.
Then the next line does not matter.
For the most part, I've never needed to ever take a look or understand it.
It's metadata about the files that are being compared.
Each file actually gets its own hash.
That's what we're seeing here.
But really it doesn't matter.
And then this is an internal file mode identifier.
Again, not important.
Then we see two lines of markers.
This is its way of telling us that for file a, whatever that is, it's going to be indicated.
Changes in file A will be indicated with a minus sign and file B will be a plus sign.
So that part's hopefully straightforward.
Then we get to chunks.
So you might have a file that's 10,000 lines long.
You change one line, get diff is not going to show you the entire 10,000 lines.
It's going to show you the change, that part that was changed.
And then a little bit of context before and after.
So we can see here's what was changed and then there's some context before and it's at the end of the
file.
So there's nothing after here.
I change this line here, so we get a little bit of context before and then some after.
And then here's another change.
We got context before and after.
So this file itself might have been a couple of hundred lines, I think it is, but it's only showing
us a small selection, a small chunk around each change.
So each chunk starts with a chunk header, which looks like, oh, here's just multiple chunks.
By the way, this is one file main CSS, it has one chunk, and then a second chunk, just two different
areas in the file that were changed.
So a chunk header is the header at the beginning of each chunk and you can identify them by the two
at signs on either side and then some weird looking numbers inside.
All right.
So there are two pairs of numbers, one set of.
These numbers corresponds to file A, the other file B.
That's what the minus sign here indicates.
So minus minus as we see is for file.
A plus is for file B.
Anyway, what these numbers are telling us is how many lines have been extracted in this trunk.
So how big is this trunk from?
File A and what part of the file do they start from?
So it's kind of confusing.
You often don't.
I personally don't spend a lot of time looking at this.
I'm usually looking at the changes, but just so you understand how to read it, this first bit says
from file A because the minus sign four lines have been extracted starting from line three.
So this is not negative three, it's just three.
The minus indicates a so four lines starting from line three.
And so the next part from file B, we have five lines starting from line three.
So I'm going to diagram that out here.
This is what our files looked like.
This is file A, this is file B, old version from the last commit, new version, same file.
But just what's changed?
Well, the chunk says from file A, we get four lines starting from line three.
One, two, three.
This is line three.
We get four lines.
Yellow, green, blue, purple.
Then file B is going to include five lines starting from line three.
One, two, three.
So one, two, three, four, five.
Now, one thing that is kind of confusing is that it shows orange right here.
This is line two of our file.
Technically, this is not really part of the trunk itself, depending on the language of your file,
if it's Python or JavaScript or something else, sometimes it will display a little preview of a line.
Other times this is something else.
It's not reliably a line from the junk.
It's confusing.
So it starts here anyway.
So what we have here are the two ranges, right?
Those numbers three, comma, four, three, comma, five, and then down below we have the actual changes.
So this is the content of the file two files superimposed where we can see every line that starts with
the minus.
It was a change that came from file A and every line that starts with the plus comes from file B.
So these lines, yellow, green, blue are unchanged, right?
They exist in both.
But then purple, which is actually red.
But purple has that minus sign came from file A and it's not in file B and then Indigo and Violet came
from file B, they are not in file A, usually get picks A and B for us in such a way that you can think
of file A is like the old stuff and file B is the new stuff, but it doesn't always work out that way.
So this tells us, as we already know, that yellow, green and blue are in both files.
Nothing changed there, right?
Red orange are both in there, too.
They're just not part of this chunk because it just picks a small little bit of context around a change.
And the change happened right there.
Purple turn to indigo and violet.
So indigo and violet are new, purple gone.
So here's a more complicated example.
This is for a stylesheet CSS.
We can see up top same file just compared A and B, then we see the chunk header.
And then here's our chunk some context and we see that we ended up with four new lines in this chunk
added as part of file B and then here the second chunk in the same file, it just skips down.
We're starting at what line 63 now instead of 22.
There's a whole bunch of stuff in between that just doesn't show up.
We see that file a had these lines in red that are gone and file B has these what, six lines that are
new.
So that's a basic concept for how these diffs, these outputs work.
If we just go back here, I know it's kind of crazy to look at, but hopefully you can step through
and understand what each line does.
So this is telling us we're comparing two files, same name, just at different points in time.
What those points in time are, we can set up our self.
We'll learn how to do that in the next couple of videos and then we see this stuff, the metadata we
really don't need to care about.
Then we see each version A and B are both assigned a symbol, A gets minus, B gets plus.
Then we have the chunk header.
It tells us seven lines from line 25 are coming from file A and seven lines starting at line 25 are
coming from file B.
Then what we see here are those seven lines from file A, right, one, two, three.
This one came from A, so four, five, six, seven and the seven lines from file B one, two, three.
Skip that one, four, five, six, seven.
And then of course, the color coding is helpful, but this minus sign means it's a file, a line that
only exists in file.
A This means it only exists in file B Usually this means old versus new.
And then we've got a second chunk in the same file where there's just a line that I added chickens that
only exists in file.
B Nothing was removed or changed in file A at this point.
And then we've got other files, right?
The same sort of idea applies to this different file or to this JavaScript file.
There are different chunks.
Excerpted.
Excerpt.
X.
I don't know how you say that for an excerpt from the files.
All right.
So in the next video, we'll talk about different ways that we can use get diff and to make different
comparisons where we will see very similar looking outputs that follow the same pattern.