The next version we'll look at is git diff head.
So this will list all changes in our working directory since the last commit since head.
Right.
Remember head is this pointer, this reference to the last commit and typically the last commit on a
branch.
So wherever head is when we do get diff head, we'll see the changes that we've made since head.
So that includes if we try this again here get diff head that includes staged and unstaged changes.
So right now we see the same exact output that we saw when I just did regular get diff.
This is showing all unstaged changes.
This is showing everything that has changed since our last commit since head.
However, if I stage something, if I do get add and then our file is called what colors text if I do
get diff again now we don't see any changes.
Right.
Nothing is showing up because this is supposed to show me the difference between my working directory
and the staging area.
And right now they're the same.
But if I do get diff head this is showing me the difference between the head and my working directory.
So now we see the same thing we were seeing earlier.
So now let's go ahead and commit.
So get commit m just add indigo and then I'm going to do something different.
Now I'm going to make what should I do?
I guess I'll make a new file and this new file will be called it doesn't really matter, but it will
be numbers.
All right.
So touch numbers dot txt and in this numbers file, I'm just going to add the number one to begin with.
So I'll just spell it out in all caps one OC.
So currently numbers is untracked.
So if I try and do get diff, I'm not going to see anything there.
However if I add that new change, so get add numbers dot txt.
Now if I do get diff head, we see that since our last commits we have some new stuff.
Right.
And it's just the fact that numbers text now exists and it has this line one inside of it.
The way that we can tell that there was nothing there before the version A is actually dev slash null.
That's gets a way of telling us nothing compared to now having the file numbers.
So there was nothing really to compare it before, but that doesn't break it.
We just end up seeing only the additions because they're only our additions.
So get diff head shows us that.
But just one more time get diff on its own.
It's only showing us unstaged changes.
Nothing has been or nothing is currently unstaged.
But if I add violet for example to colors and I do get diff, we only see a diff for colors because
that's the only file that changed that has not been staged versus get diff head.
If I just remind you here numbers is staged colors is not so if I do get diff head I see all changes
staged on stage.
It doesn't matter anything new in the working directory since head right and head if you ever forget
and head currently is pointing to this commit here so that's what we are comparing to so get diff shows
us all unstaged changes get diff head shows us all changes staged and unstaged since head.