Another variation of git diff is to pass in this option dash dash staged or alternatively cached.
They do the same thing, just an alias.
Both of them will show us the staged changes, only the changes that are staged.
So we've seen how to do all unstaged, we've seen how to do staged and on staged this.
Both of these options are how you do only stage changes, only show me the staged changes.
What is the difference between my last commit and the staging area?
So I'll show this to you.
Now, if we take a look at git status, the same project.
Project is a stretch but the same repository changes to be committed numbers text.
We added one into numbers, then we have some changes for the colors file we added violet, but that
is not part of the staging area.
So right now if I do a if I can type it, get diff dash, dash and then staged, we only see those changes
from numbers because that's the change versus if I do get diff on its own.
This is unstaged changes.
So we see colours and if I do get diff head, we see both.
Right.
That's everything that has changed.
It doesn't care if it's staged or not.
And then if I add in colours, so if I do get add colours now if I do get diff dash dash stage, we
see both because both of those changes have been staged at this point.
Also we can use cached for whatever reason.
I don't like cache to think just I call the staging area stage makes more sense to me.
But I do believe the docs actually reference cache first and then say stage is an alias of cached.
It doesn't matter.
All right.
So quick quiz here.
What will we see?
Here's my git status.
Well, let's see if I do get diff.
Think about it.
The answer is nothing.
Well, I guess we see end, but there's no changes to display because get diff is showing us unstaged
changes.
There are no unstaged changes.
Everything has been staged at this point.