Another thing we can do is narrow down the diff to a specific file or files.
So instead of just everything right, all on stage changes or are all stage changes or all changes since
head whatever we're actually looking at, we can narrow it down and say only in this one file.
So currently we don't have a lot going on here that we would want to narrow down.
But if I do get def, get def, get diff staged as we saw in the last video, I'm getting two files.
I'm looking at all changes that are currently staged, but I could say actually only show me the numbers
file how that has changed and that's exactly what we see.
So as an example, let's say I have this really large project I've been working on.
I showed a couple of videos ago where there's a lot of CSS and I made a lot of changes in this main
CSS, and I want to see what those changes are since the last commit so I can do get diff head.
But there are other files I changed to right index html main css.
But also there's another file I changed JavaScript file here.
You can see that and this is still not a whole lot of changes.
Let's say it's been a couple of hours.
I just want to see the changes since my last commit to my CSS file main CSS.
So this is the path style slash main CSS.
I can narrow it down, get diff and then style slash main CSS.
And specifically what I want is get diff head because I want to see all changes staged over on Unstaged
since the last commit in that one file and that's what we see.
So these changes are specifically from this file and we can see right since the last commit I added
these lines, I added this line and I added this line.
Really it's I modified, right?
I edited a line, but it doesn't show it that way.
It says this came from file A, it's gone in file B and this came from file B.
It's not in file A.
All right.
So that's how we can narrow it down to a particular file.
I can also do multiple, for example.
There's also an index, that HTML file.
I just separate them by spaces and now I have two files.
I'm looking at the diff for the main css and for index html.
So this also works.
If I want to see the stage changes, I don't think I have any.
Nope.
They're all unstaged.
But if I wanted to, I could do dash dash stage or dash dash cache and other variations.
I can narrow it down to a particular file or files.