I can also get dif to compare changes between two branches.
So if I have two branches currently I don't in the repo I was showing you, but whatever branch one
is and branch two are get will do a diff between the files in those branches.
So all the files in those branches, although you can narrow it down as well.
So let's do a quick demo of that.
I need to make a branch, so why don't I commit the changes?
I added what indigo and I added Violet and I added my numbers file.
Let's just go with add violet and create numbers and then I'll add a couple of numbers here.
One, two, three, four, get status.
Let's do clear this, get commit a am.
Add more numbers.
All righty.
And now if I make a branch.
So I'm going to create a new branch.
Get switch, dash.
See?
We'll call this branch about odd numbers.
So on this branch, I'm only going to have odd numbers.
So I'm going to delete two and I'll delete four.
I'll do a commit, so I'll add numbers, then I'll commit removed two and four, and then let's also
add five down at the bottom.
So we'll do a git, add numbers, get commit, add five OC.
So right now we have two branches.
Nothing very exciting, but we have master and odd numbers.
And if I want to do a comparison between the two of them, I want to see what has changed from master
to odd numbers or vice versa.
The order does matter, but I list the two branches and I separate them by two dots.
Or you can actually just add a space.
Both of them will do the same thing.
So let's do.
Let's do from master to odd numbers first.
So get diff master dot dot odd numbers.
And the only file that changed was numbers.
We still have the colors file on both branches, but there's no differences, so there's nothing to
display.
Now here we can see that numbers dot text version A, which is from the master branch.
Because of that order that I wrote, Master, two odd numbers.
This one is from the master branch and this one is from my odd numbers branch.
So we see that on the master branch, which is a it has the minus sign in front of it.
That's its designated symbol.
We had one, two, three, four and we did not have this stuff right.
Then on B, we have the plus sign as its symbol.
So we had one, three and then five.
So that's new on the odd numbers branch and it does not include two and four.
If I change the order, get diff odd numbers and then master.
Now we see things have flipped.
So A has been assigned the minus sign but a this time is the odd numbers branch and B is master.
So here right on the master branch.
B with the plus sign we have one, two, three, four, and it's the opposite of what we saw previously.
So that order does matter.
Also, just to make this clear, we get the same outcome if we just use a space, but people like to
use the dot dot, maybe it makes it I don't know, it makes it clearer, you know, that you're doing
that comparison, but you'll see both of them.
And then let me just quickly change one of these files.
So let's do red, orange, yellow, green, blue, indigo, violets.
I don't know.
Odd numbers will only display the odd numbered color.
So if this is one, get rid of two, that's three.
We get rid of four, five and six.
I don't know.
I might have totally screwed that up, but whatever.
We have fewer colors here.
So now we type get status.
Let's make a commit here.
So I'll add the colors file and we'll just go with remove some colors.
All right.
So now if I do a get diff, let's go from master to odd numbers again.
We have two files that are showing up.
So the colors file changed from master to odd numbers.
Right on master, which is a we had orange, green and indigo.
They are not present on the odd numbers branch and we didn't add anything new.
But on the numbers file we have the same thing we saw earlier.
We don't need to go over it again.
So now we have multiple files because there were changes to multiple files between those branches.
So that's how you compare branches with git diff, dot dot or a space between two branch names.