The last variation we'll take a look at is comparing to comets.
If you want to know what changed between two comets, not necessarily head right.
It could be any comet in the past.
We can use the same syntax, get dif and then some commit hash, dot, dot, some other comet hash.
So why don't we go back to master get log.
Let's do one line if I want to know what changed between I don't know.
Add red so that commit and add blue and purple.
Sure.
If I want to know what changed there, I need to start by copying one of these comet hashes.
It's kind of annoying actually to keep track of both of them.
I'm just going to paste it in this file.
And then the second one I wanted was this comet hash.
All right, let's see what happened there.
So get diff and then the first one.
Dot, dot.
The second one.
And we see the only file that changed was colors.
That's the only file, really?
Well.
We did introduce the numbers file, but after this commit.
So it didn't even exist in either of these commits.
But you can see the changes, right?
We added all this stuff into the file between those two commits and they're not necessarily consecutive
commits.
It's just all changes between those two commits.
And this also works if I have a space just like with two branches.
Same diff.
All right.
So to recap those different versions, you can compare changes between two commits.
The order matters just like it does with two branches.
So all changes between all files for two different branches or two different commits.
Then we saw that we can do the same thing but actually narrow it down to one file or two or three.
We just call those files out afterwards.
So that also works for branches and commits and we saw that we can use the dash, dash staged or cached
option to only see the changes that are staged to see unstaged changes only we can use get diff and
then to see all changes since the last commit.
So everything that's new in the working directory staged or unstaged get diff head.