So the last thing I'll show you here is how to use get cracking or a similar gooey tool to visualize
diffs to actually see them in a file instead of having to see them in your terminal.
A lot of the time this is really useful, especially if you're working on large projects with tons of
files.
And this is one of the areas I think always shine when you're working with Git.
So here's get cracking.
Unfortunately, as I've said a couple of times before, I can't make this any larger, so it lets me
make it larger up until this point, which is still not very large.
So I'll do my best to try and enhance and zoom in in post-production.
But here's my colors repository.
Very simple, right?
We have our initial commit, we added red, orange, yellow, green, add blue and purple had indigo.
Then I created this odd numbers branch.
Right.
I removed two and four from the numbers.
It's this project file here, numbers and colors.
If I visually if I want to see a diff, let's start by making some unstaged changes right now.
Right.
Get status.
Nothing to commit working tree clean.
So why don't I add something to colors like I love the rainbow.
We'll save that.
And then in numbers, let's add five.
This is on the master branch.
Six and seven like that.
All right, so now I have two files that have been changed, both of which are unstaged.
So now, as it shows me here to file changes in working directory, I can click to view those changes.
So that's what it's showing me here.
Unstaged and staged.
So I can click on either these files and it visually shows me this new change showing it to me in the
file here.
I love the Rainbow was added it shows it in green so you can see there.
Also, here's our little diff header.
It's not showing the entire file right.
I can see I can click to see file view or just diff view.
And then same thing with numbers here.
It's showing me that five, six and seven are new.
They've been added.
Let's do something slightly different.
Let's delete for whatever reason.
I don't know.
We'll get rid of Violet.
Okay.
So now go back to colors and it's showing me violet that has been removed it's non existent currently
versus I love the rainbow has been added and again it's just showing me the diff view and then if I
wanted to, if I stage one of these files, let's stage colors.
I can go here and see.
Okay, here's the changes I have staged.
Here's the changes I've unstaged.
So if I stage both files and I just want to see that diff now, I can just go between them.
Nothing has changed in terms of what is what's different and what's not different.
It's just if I was doing this with Git commands, I would do get diff versus get diff head versus git
get diff staged here.
It's just a matter of clicking.
If they're in the stage two files area, then I'm viewing a diff for what is staged.
If they are not staged here, I'm looking at the unstaged changes from numbers, dot text, other things
that we can do.
If I get out of here quickly.
Sometimes I you get lost.
Here it is.
Can X out.
If I want to see changes between two commits, for example, I can click on one commit like where we
added indigo and then hold down shift and select another commit like that.
And then over here it's showing me viewing diff between two commits.
There's only one file that changed and this is what changed, right?
This is the difference between them.
So I removed purple, I added indigo between those two commits or let's do a more drastic difference
from the very beginning.
Or How about when we added red up to when we added indigo?
Here's what changed.
Or I could have multiple files involved.
I'll open a different project.
Here's a much larger project.
That 2048 app I was showing you right where we had the more complicated diffs.
If I wanted to visually see the difference between some commits, I could.
I don't know.
Let's just pick two early commits.
How about.
Sure.
Those two.
I can see all of these files were changed.
Although it looks like ten of them were renamed, but four files were modified.
And then I can see the different chunks.
I can see the chunk headers.
So this is visually for me, a lot easier.
It's often a lot easier to work with if I really am trying to understand the difference between two
commits or between two two branches or something like that.
Doing it from the command line.
Good to know how to do and I still use that.
But if I really need to dig down into the changes and spend some time working through what's different,
then I really like the diff view from editors or from guys like get cracking.
So if I want to see the same thing that I'm seeing over here and I just type get diff head, this is
everything that's changed since the last commits very early in the section.
I think the first or second video I changed index HTML, I changed grid JS and I changed main CSS so
I can view that here I click on my work in progress.
So this is nothing committed yet.
And then I can see the three files one at a time.
Here's what's changed in index.
I can visualize it pretty easy.
I can stage, I can see what changed in the grid JS file and in main course.
So I find this just better, easier to work with than this personally.
And the last thing I'll show you is if you want more context, you want the entire file.
Right now we're in hunk.
People call it hunk instead of chunk.
Sometimes they mean the same thing.
I'm viewing one chunk or one hunk at a time versus in line view shows me the entire file with the diff
right there so I can find that one down there.
It's not too bad, but some of the files are longer.
Right.
So I've got a scroll quite a ways if I want to see everything versus if I go to Hunk View, I just see
the three hunks with some context around each change.
So that's it.
Nice part of get cracking and all these other guys, they pretty much all offer a view like this.
It's pretty standard.