Okay.
So it's time to get some practice with git diff.
There are two very important announcements or notes about this exercise up front.
First of all, this exercise actually involves an existing repository that you're going to download.
So stay tuned for those instructions in just a moment.
And second, the other important note is that all these different variations that I'm asking you to
use in these these different steps here, you may not remember them all off the top of your head.
I wouldn't blame you if you don't.
So don't feel like we've talked about adding and committing and branching.
Those are like fundamental things you do day to day defying.
You may do frequently, but maybe not every flavor of git diff.
So I would say it's just not as crucial if you struggle to remember some of these.
I wouldn't feel bad, but make sure you can get the answers.
Make sure you understand what command does what.
Even if you can't recall it instantly, it's fine to look things up anyway.
Like all the other exercises, there's a link in the resources for this video.
I definitely recommend you open it up because in order to get started with this project, with this
exercise, it's not really a project you're going to need to do something we have not yet seen.
This is actually skipping ahead.
We're going to learn about a get command once we get to GitHub called Get Clone.
So all that I'll say about it for now is that as part of the setup for this exercise, you need to copy
this link or copy this entire line.
So I'm going to do that right now, and then we're going to run this from our terminal and we're going
to make sure we're not in a git repository when we do this, because this is actually going to make
a copy of a git repo that I've made.
It's going to make a copy for you on your machine.
So let's try it.
I'll do it right here.
So I'm not in a get repository right now and I'm going to run this command.
I just copied it.
I don't want those when I copied it.
I don't want the little marks there.
So now I'm going to hit Enter.
And we get this output from Git again.
We're going to learn about this command later, but I now have a new folder called Git diff exercise.
So now I'm going to seed into that.
That's the next step change into that directory.
So seed and to get diff exercise and you'll see two files in here.
So I can open this code dot.
Just open it in vs code and here we go.
We have two files, one for Fleetwood Mac, txt van, Fleetwood Mac and then another one for Queen,
the band Queen.
Now the way that this exercise works is that there are actually two branches.
The current branch that you're on by default is called current.
Now I recognize it's kind of confusing, but I meant is that this is the branch for the current lineup's,
the modern 2021, 2022 lineups of these bands.
But there's a second branch that I've made already and you can access it by running this command.
Get switch 1970s.
So I'll do that now.
And it is kind of weird.
You're not going to see this branch, which is why I'm having you run this.
If you run git branch, we don't see a second branch, we will learn why that is.
So I'm not going to go into that until we get to GitHub and remote branches.
But anyway, just follow these steps blindly.
It's okay, we will learn.
So now I have two branches, 1970s and current.
I made both of those ahead of time for you.
Now you have them on your machine if you follow these steps.
So if we look at the 1970s branch, that's what I'm on right now.
We have some slight changes.
For example, the queen file now has Freddie Mercury as its singer.
Fleetwood Mac has a different lineup.
No keyboardist back in 1970.
Now, this band, Fleetwood Mac, has had like a million lineup changes.
And this is not entirely faithful.
But the point is that there's two versions of each file two branches.
Each branch has the same two file names, but different contents.
So now that we have that setup, we now have our diffs, the actual exercise portion.
So there are a bunch of steps where I'm asking you to make different comparisons between the 1970s branch
and the current branch for all files between the 1970s branch and the current branch, but only for
the Queen text file.
Or switch over to this current branch.
That's the name of it and run a diff to compare the current head to the previous commit.
Basically there's a bunch of diffs I'm asking you to run.
Everyone will involve a flavor of git diff.
Now towards the end I actually ask you to make some changes to a file.
Follow these directions pretty carefully.
For example, here, I'm telling you to replace Adam Lambert's name with your own name.
Save the change, add to the staging area.
So add that change, but do not commit.
So that sort of thing is important because it enables us to run different diffs where some changes are
staged, some are not staged and some are committed anyway.
Follow these instructions if you'd like.
I hope you do this exercise.
We're going to make some comparisons between the different band lineups over the years and stop watching
at this point because I'm now just going to go through it myself.
So I did part one.
I have this repository, I have these two branches, right?
1970s in current.
Now the first exercise, the first problem is to compare the difference between the 1970s branch and
the current branch across all files.
So I can do that with git diff and then just two branch names.
So I didn't specify which one you should compare.
First, remember that the order matters, but I'll just say 1970s compared to now chronologically that
makes more sense because.
Well, let me just show you.
We see, for example, what's changed like currently in Fleetwood Mac.
Lindsey Buckingham is no longer part of the band, sadly, and he's been replaced.
So this format makes sense in my opinion.
Where we have the old is the actual chronologically older branch and the new is the current branch,
but it doesn't matter.
So we also see keyboard was set to none on the 1970s.
Branch There was no keyboard player and now in the current branch it's Christine McVie.
And we also see the changes in the Queen file.
Now the second part of the exercise is to do the same thing, but only for the Queen txt file.
So still compare the two branches.
But I can narrow it down just like that as a third value.
Just give me that one file and here we are.
What's changed?
Well, Freddie Mercury exists in the 1970s branch.
Adam Lambert is in the current branch.
Mike GROSS is in the 1970s branch.
And Neil Fairclough, I don't know.
He's a new addition to the band, actually.
What's his name?
Roger Deacon, I think was his name.
What's the real the main basis of the band.
But he's actually not part of it anymore.
So he kind of got lost between 1970s and 2021.
But we don't have a middle branch anyway.
Next.
Step.
Step three, switch over to the current branch if you're not on it currently.
So I'll do that.
I'm on the 1970s branch get switch to current and then it says run a diff to compare the current head
to the previous commit.
Basically if we do a git log, I want to see what happened between where we are right now.
This is head and this commit.
So there are multiple ways of doing this.
I mean, I could copy these commit hashes and do a diff between them or I could just say what's the
difference?
So get diff between head and then the prior commit the parent of head head tilde one and this is what
changed in that commit I changed the basis.
John Deacon I think I said.
Roger Deacon It's John Deacon anyway, I updated him.
He left the band and was replaced by this guy.
So the way that I've written this right now is that we're looking at head compared to head.
Tilde one I would probably do it this way instead like this so that we can see what was added in the
newest commit and what was removed.
Right?
It's the same change.
It's just the order was slightly different, but you could also get that commit hash, as I mentioned,
so we could just copy part of that hash or the whole thing and do a get diff compared to that.
So this is the same thing as this.
And then here we're just flipping the order.
So this is comparing head tilted one to head and this is comparing head to head till day one.
So the new commit to the parent or the parent commit to the child the next step while on the current
branch change the queen txt file by replacing Adam Lambert with your own name.
Save the change.
Add that file to the staging area.
Do not commit OC.
So let's try that.
I'm going to change.
Adam Lambert.
And put my own name.
Cold steel.
And I'm going to save.
And then I will just run, get status, I will add that file, I'll stage it like the instructions say,
but I'm not going to commit now.
Edit The Fleetwood Mac File Changing the lead singer from Stevie Nicks to Stevie Nicks.
One of my chickens is Stevie Nicks, so we'll save that file, but we're not going to stage it.
So Stevie Nicks becomes Stevie Nicks and I saved it, but I'm not going to stage that.
Okay.
Now we get to do some more diffs.
Run a diff that reveals the unstaged changes in the working directory.
So I should only see the change that we made to Fleetwood Mac dot txt.
So what is the command I can do to view that?
Well, it's going to be get diff something and it's actually it's just get diff.
So get diff on its own.
It's going to show me in this case the UNSTAGED changes.
It's not going to show me the changes that I already staged.
Right.
To do that.
That's the next little bit here.
Run a diff that would reveal only the stage changes.
So I should only see that change we made to queen txt.
I should see my name.
So how do I do that?
Well, it's going to be another git diff, but we need dash dash staged or cached and there we are.
We see cold steel or whatever your name is replacing Adam Lambert and then finally run a diff that prints
all changes.
Both files that we changed the stage file and the unstaged file since the prior commit so we can do
get diff head.
So take the current working directory staged and unstaged changes.
Compare that to the head commit.
So here's what changed in Fleetwood Mac and here's what changed in Queen OC.
So I know this is kind of a tedious exercise, but I had to try and come up with something that you
could follow along with and try and run some diffs on your own and get some practice with the different
commands.
You know, I don't know how successful this was, but I hope you followed along and enjoyed it.
Don't get hung up on this bit around Git clone and how this all works.
We will be spending a lot of time on that later on.
This just enabled me to give you some starter code or files and branches so you could just get going
with the diffs.
All right.
Moving on.