So next up, I'd like to talk about the course curriculum and what we cover.
And I'll try to break it down into some smaller pieces because on the surface we cover quite a few topics
related to Git and GitHub.
So there's always a pressure honestly in these courses to fit as many related topics as possible into
a course just to compete or to stand out in some way.
And I can't ignore that, but I do want to try my best to make it very clear what actually matters and
what is fundamental, because not all of this stuff you see in front of you and there's likely to be
more by the time you're actually watching this, there will be more videos or more additional sections
added towards the end because students request them.
But anyway, not all of these are critical.
So there's a couple of chunks, I guess that I would I would break things down into the first bit is
all about the core functionality of Git working with the very, very basics.
Things like adding and committing and creating repositories get logged, get status, creating branches,
checking out, switching, merging.
That is your core git toolbox.
And then we talk about I'm calling it next level git, but it's not crazy difficult stuff.
It's just a couple of git topics that won't come up as often.
They're not part of your day to day get life, but they still are very important.
So we talk about defying the git diff, command stashing, and then we talk about quite a few ways of
time traveling and git or undoing changes.
Get revert, get reset, get restored, undoing changes and going back to old work and detaching and
reattaching the head.
And there's quite a bit of stuff in that section.
So it's important, but it's just not part of this Git core.
Then we move on to GitHub and collaboration.
So I've grouped together four sections here.
I don't really have a nice title for it, but we basically learn about the basics of GitHub, working
with GitHub, getting our code up on GitHub, getting stuff down from GitHub.
We talk about things like GitHub pages and GitHub gists and collaboration workflows.
That's a very significant chunk of this course.
We spend a lot of time on that, talking about the different ways that you could use Git with a team
to collaborate along with GitHub and different structures, different strategies you can employ.
There's not just one way and they all have some certain strengths and weaknesses.
So I demonstrate those and spend a lot of time talking about it.
It's pretty important stuff.
So I've grouped that together with GitHub and then after that it's kind of just a mixture of other Git
stuff that I felt compelled to include.
And these are some of the more advanced topics or the niche topics.
So this includes things like rebasing, cleaning up your git history with interactive rebasing, squashing,
dropping, fixing up all sorts of sort of fun parts, in my opinion.
We talk about tags, we talk about how it works behind the scenes and hashing.
We cover things like get objects, get blobs, get trees.
So there's stuff in here that you could go your whole life as a get user without knowing.
I think it's worth giving you the option at least to check it out.
If you're curious, we talk about creating custom aliases and shortcuts and ref logs.
That's a fun one.
I'm happy with how that section turned out and as I said, there's likely to be more.
If you scroll down right now through the curriculum, there's likely more content in the course that's
not included here.
So to recap this, there's quite a bit and it's all getting GitHub oriented, but there's this first
chunk that is the core of Git on its own.
Then we talk about some next level Git topics that are absolutely important to know, but they're not
part of your typical hour to hour or day to day use case for Git or they might not be.
And then we talk about GitHub and collaboration workflows and then it's just a bunch of other Git related
topics at the end that I had a lot of fun recording.
Okay, so let's get started.