Next up, I'd like to talk about who uses Git.
So this will be pretty quick as well and optional.
You don't have to know about this in order to use it.
But the first most obvious group would be engineers, developers, coders ranging from people who work
on their own little tiny side projects or just hobby projects.
Entrepreneurs up to massive tech giants like Facebook and Google Get is the most commonly used version
control system, as we talked about.
And when you're developing applications, version control is very, very important to use.
On its official home page, they list some of the companies that use it Google, Facebook, Microsoft,
Twitter, LinkedIn, Netflix.
And then if you go to a website like Stack Share where you can view I don't know how accurate Stack
share is, but you can view different tools and companies that use them.
There's other companies like Robinhood, Reddit, Lyft, stack share itself uses get smaller companies,
Patreon, Fiverr, Canva.
I use Canva all the time.
Massive companies like Walmart.
Anyway, the point is it's used by pretty much any engineering team you can think of.
Also, another group that uses Git or at least would benefit from being familiar with Git are tech adjacent
roles.
So people who are not developers but work with developers or deal with developers learning the basics
of git.
It's not all that difficult and it can help a lot with conversations, with deadlines, with just setting
expectations.
And in particular, designers often need the basic understanding to be able to work with Git and communicate
with developers.
So another completely separate group of people who are using Get these days are governments and large
organizations, not technical.
They're not I don't know tech startups governments use get a lot to manage the drafting of laws, collaboration
of drafting laws, sharing data and large data sets.
So Washington DC City Council uses Git and GitHub.
We'll talk about GitHub in a bit to publish its laws and have made it a collaborative process and citizens
have actually found and fixed typos collaboratively in those laws.
They fix them using Git.
So I think I have some examples.
Here we are.
This is the city of Chattanooga.
They use GitHub, which again we'll talk about what GitHub is and how it compares to Git.
But all you need to know is that it's based on Git.
So this project is simple.
It just shares parking locations in the city of Chattanooga.
And then if we go to GitHub Web page, they have something called Government GitHub.
They they show actually a whole bunch of different governments that use GitHub, which again is built
on top of Git.
So governments, groups from Argentina, Australia, the US, the UK, I mean pretty much every country
is listed here.
Now that doesn't mean that Git plays a central role in all of these governments.
For example, let's see USGS, the US Geological Survey, they have a whole bunch of things on GitHub
pages and pages of these projects that are shared with the public and they use Git to manage all of
them anyway.
So that's another group that use it these days.
Scientists also more and more are using Git to help collaborate on projects to share findings and data
sets to manage code and work together on code bases and get in GitHub together.
Really work well in an open source or a peer reviewed world like science and research.
We'll learn more about GitHub.
I keep saying that, but we will.
And some other groups, writers, not all writers.
Certainly it's not that common these days, but some writers really are becoming fans of Git.
I listened to some screenwriting podcasts to fall asleep to sometimes and every so often there's an
episode about using Git to write screenplays, manage versions, write.
I talked about having different essay versions.
Well, with a screenplay you've got so many revisions, so many drafts or a novel, so many characters,
so many ways of structuring a novel, ordering things different arcs.
So Git is definitely gaining in popularity there.
And then specifically, I've seen multiple use cases of Git for collaborative textbook writing where
textbooks usually have multiple authors.
So this is a book, a textbook on informal homo topi.
I think it's homo topi type theory.
I have no clue what it is.
What the book I mean, this means nothing to me other than the fact that it's a textbook on something
crazy sounding.
But a lot of people have used this textbook.
It looks like a couple of thousand people have started.
So it's like a favorite of their projects on GitHub.
And here we'll see.
There's 85 people who have collaborated to write this textbook.
Just one simple example.
Now the last slide, anyone really can use it.
People find all sorts of creative uses from keeping a daily diary to writing their PhD thesis with Get
All the Way to composers.
I saw a Reddit comment from a music composer who writes symphonies and he uses Git to help track the
massive changes, all the different files, the parts as his symphonies evolve over time.
It's a month, multiple month process to write a symphony for a full orchestra with all the different
instruments written out.
He uses Git to help with that.
So I assume a lot of you who are watching this are probably in this group right there, or maybe this
group.
But increasingly I expect in the next few years there'll be more governments, more scientists, more
writers, more symphony composers who use Git.
Because it really can be, I won't say a life changer, maybe a life saver.
It can save you a lot of stress and time down the line, assuming you can get past the initial hurdle
of learning it.
We are on the precipice of learning it, so I'll shut up.